Well, wait, it's long.
Okay, it looks like the transcription is turned off for the meeting organizer by organizing policy.
Okay, I suppose the recording has no problem.
Previously, I can see the transcript to guarantee the recording is on, but today I cannot.
So I suppose the recording is on and it can record my voice.
But there's no transcript.
Stop.
Turn on.
Do it here.
Start.
Okay, I suppose the recording is fine, okay?
Because the mic here is on, although I cannot see the transcript.
Okay, anyway, the recording isn't on.
Sure.
Here is start recording.
Start recording.
Okay, so we start.
Okay, last time we talked about the lecture three about cryptography.
So we finished part one about the summation encryption.
In summation encryption, we have the idea that both the sender and the receiver, they share the same key, K.
Key K will be used for both encryption and decryption.
And we have the common null encryption algorithm and decryption algorithm.
Just like in this example, we use AES.
Well, in this summation encryption, only the key K will be secret.
Others, like the encryption algorithm and decryption algorithm, will know to everyone.
So this model, and we talked about the SIDA CIFR.
So SIDA CIFR is easy to be attacked because we can try all possible cases, right?
Just like in this example, we can use a brute force attack.
The key K can be tested from 1 to 25.
Then we talk about the one-time path.
The one-time path is only null, perfect, secrecy scheme.
However, one-time path is quite difficult to be applied in the reality, in the real world.
Because one-time path requires the key length.
The key length will be the same as your plaintext.
In part two, we talked about the public key scheme.
Particularly, we talked about the RSA algorithm.
So in this RSA algorithm, we show the mechanism.
Why do we have the RSA algorithm?
From the Euler's theorem, how we can generate the public key and the private key here.
So according to our previous knowledge in the module inverse Euclidean algorithm,
we can derive the public key and private key to make sure that the ED and DNE, the module inverse, mod phi n.
So we know what's the meaning for phi n.
So this is a real example to see how we can, based on the given PQ value, we have the n value.
n is a product of P and Q.
And because n is a product of two primes, so phi n equals P minus 1 times Q minus 1.
Once we know the phi n, and also we know the public key E to be 5 here,
we are able to calculate the module inverse of E to be D.
So D is the private key.
With public key and private key, we can apply the RSA algorithm to calculate the subtext C from the original message M.
So M to the E mod n is C.
And from C, we can get back to its original message M to apply C to the D mod n.
And also we can see we can use CRT, this theorem, to accelerate our calculation of the big numbers.
Their exponential operation mod big number n.
So this can allow us to quickly get the result for this mod operation.
In part three, we took about another very important concept.
It is a Diffie-Hellman algorithm.
So this one will allow two parties to calculate the secret key K.
So they can share this key K, KKA equals KB, to guarantee that they have the same symmetric key K for the future complications.
So the security is guaranteed that we took about the discrete log algorithm.
So in the next lecture, in this exponential operation, just like Alice chooses A, Bob chooses B,
Alice will calculate small x from GA mod P.
But even this x is sent to anyone else.
So no one will know the chosen A by Alice.
The reason is because this is a discrete log problem.
So actually it is very hard.
Without knowing the A, only with the value of x, it is impossible to calculate the small a in this Diffie-Hellman algorithm.
The Diffie-Hellman algorithm will allow two people to get the same symmetric key K to be used in the symmetric encryption.
So now we look at part four.
So part four will provide you some knowledge about the public key cryptography, what's the requirement, and how we can look at their security for the RSA algorithm.
So for RSA algorithm, its security is guaranteed by the factorization of a big number.
To factorize, we say factorization is to factorize n to be the product of P and Q.
So this process is very difficult, given n to be a very large number, to be like 1024 bits.
If you want to get its corresponding P and Q, that would be very difficult.
So suppose n is one of 24 bits.
What's the size for P and Q?
P and Q, the size will be what?
How many bits for P and Q?
If we suppose n is 1024 bits.
Any idea?
If it's 512, should be what?
So P and Q will be similar size to n, right?
Should be similar size.
Okay, we look at in the public key cryptography, we have different ways to apply the private key and public key.
So you can use public key in the encryption, or you can use the private key in the encryption.
So first we look at the first scheme, we use the public key in the encryption.
Just like support Bob is the sender and Alice is the receiver.
So support Bob wants to send a message n to Alice.
So this message x.
And well, Bob can use Alice's public key to do the encryption, right, to do the encryption.
Then the subtext y will be sent to Alice.
So this y is encrypted by using Alice's public key.
So only Alice has a private key, so other than Alice, no one else can do the decryption.
So Alice can use her private key to do the decryption and get back the original message x.
So this y in the RSA algorithm, we know that the public key is e and n, right?
And private key is d.
So this y equals x to the e mod n.
And to do the decryption, Alice will apply her private key.
So to get back x equals the subtext y to the private key d mod n.
OK, so this is the encryption and the decryption process.
Of course, someone can apply the second case using the private key to do the encryption.
So Bob will use his private key to do the encryption.
So this y equals x to the d mod n, right?
Well, using your private key, you can do decryption.
But anyone else can use your public key to do the decryption.
Your public key is publicly known by everyone.
So Alice can use Bob's public key to do the decryption.
So Alice can obtain the plaintext by applying y to the e mod n.
OK, so because, well, you can see this y equals x to the d e mod n.
This is x to the e d mod n.
So e d, in fact, equals x to the k times 5 plus 1 mod n, right?
Because we will choose e d is congruent to 1 mod phi n.
So according to the Euler's theorem, well, this mod n in the exponent part phi n, this one can be cancelled.
OK, normally we apply the second scheme to generate the signature.
Somehow this is not a standard way to generate the signature.
But the idea is the same.
You will use your private key to generate your signature.
And others will use your public key to do the signature verification, right?
Because only you have that unique private key.
So others can use your public key to do verification.
That message is really from Alice because the receiver is using Alice public key to do the verification.
Well, for the public key crypto systems, well, this can solve two important problems.
The concept of public key cryptography evolved from an attempt to solve two of the most difficult problems associated with the symmetric encryption.
So that means in symmetric encryption, it is very hard to get key distribution and very hard to generate the digital signatures.
Well, in the symmetric encryption, both the sender and the receiver, they should have the same key.
So before they can do encryption, decryption, they should have the same key.
How to get the same key for both sender and receiver?
We said this is a key distribution problem, right?
So in fact, it is difficult.
Well, in the public key scheme, we can use Diffie-Hellman, DH, this algorithm to provide the key distribution.
Both sides, they can, after some calculation, they can get the same key for the encryption and decryption.
So key distribution means how to have secure communications in general without having to trust.
So this is a key, the key distribution center with your key, without a trusted third party.
The second problem is called the digital signature.
So this means how to verify that a message comes intact from the claimed sender.
Well, in the public key scheme, we can use the private key of sender to do the encryption to generate the signature.
So we can use private key D of the sender to generate signature.
OK.
So the withfield Diffie and Martin Hellman from Stanford University achieved a breakthrough in 1976 by coming up with a method that addressed the key distribution problem.
So this DH algorithm will allow Alice and Bob to generate the same TK to be used in the symmetric encryption scheme.
And RSA algorithm can be used for both purposes.
Because RSA algorithm, the original message M can be used as the key.
M can be used as a key.
So this M can be generated by sender and will be decrypted, received by the receiver secretly.
So this key, this M can be regarded to be the key.
And also in previous slide, well, in the second case, in case B, well, the sender like Bob can use his private key to generate the signature.
So this is a way to generate a signature to be verified by the receiver Alice.
OK, we have talked about this one previously for the public key cryptosystem.
If the sender use the public key of the receiver, like this is A, this is B, A can use B's public key to do the encryption.
And send the self-text Y, then only the receiver B can do the decryption.
So in this way, we'll guarantee that the secrecy, this property is achieved.
But even this self-text can be obtained by some cryptoanalyst.
Well, the attacker in the middle, the attacker cannot guess, cannot calculate the private key.
And not the attacker cannot decrypt the message, cannot get the original message X.
So only B with his private key can do the decryption to get the original message X.
Well, the second method is to apply the sender's private key to generate, somehow to generate a signature.
So this signature will be verified by receiver B because B will use A's public key to do verification.
The public key of A to decrypt the message and to verify that the message is really from X, from A.
And we call this the process for authentication.
So authentication means the message is really from someone like from A, right from Alice.
Well, for receiver, I will use Alice's public key to do the verification.
So that means the message must be sent from Alice.
Only Alice has her private key.
Of course, you can use both, but you can combine them together.
Well, first, you can use your private key, A's private key, to do the encryption.
That means somehow you can regard this one to be, you generate the signature.
Then you use the receiver's public key to do the encryption again.
So this one will, to guarantee the secrecy, the message cannot be decrypted by anyone else, cannot be disclosed, be known by any others.
So at the destination part, the receiver can use corresponding decryption algorithm to get back the original message X.
When we apply the public key system, the public key scheme, we can achieve the following three functions.
The first one is for encryption and decryption.
So that means the sender can encrypt a message with a recipient's public key, right?
So that means the generated message Y can be transmitted in a public channel.
So this Y equals original message, or we call it to be C subtext, equals N to the E mod N.
So this is the encryption process.
We get the subtext and only the receiver with a private key can do the decryption.
So this is the encryption, decryption.
Or the sender can sign a message with its private key.
We say this signature will be generated by M to the D mod N.
Okay, you generate your signature and signature can be verified by receiver using your public key.
Of course, we can use the public key scheme to do the key exchange.
Just like two sides can cooperate to exchange a session key, KAB, right?
KAB in the Diffie-Hellman algorithm.
So both sides will get a key KAB equals G AB mod P, okay?
So Alice and Bob can locally choose the private data A and B.
After some data exchange, they will locally get the same key KAB.
This key KAB can be used for future message encryption in the symmetric encryption algorithm.
Some public key algorithms are suitable for all three applications.
Some can be used for only one or two.
So RSA can be used for all three, right?
Encryption, decryption, digital signature.
So this is like a message to the E.
Digital signature can be generated by message to the D and key exchange.
Key exchange means will the M to C to M, this M can be regarded as a key, okay?
So both sender, receiver, they know the M to be the key to be used by both sides.
Elliptic curve, similarly, well, this one requires some mathematical background.
Well, so we don't talk about it.
Elliptic curve is more efficient compared to the RSA.
More efficient.
Now RSA, so they can achieve all three functions.
Elliptic curve, this kind of public key scheme.
The Diffie-Hellman is used only for DH, is only used for key exchange.
And DSS is digital signature standard.
So this one is proposed by the United States.
This one is used only for digital signature generation and verification.
So this is a digital signature standard.
For the public key, this kind of scheme, it has some requirements.
The public key algorithms must fulfill the following three requirements.
The first requirement means that, well, it is computationally easy for party B to generate a pair of keys, right?
To generate the key is not difficult.
So public key, like in RSA algorithm, where public key
E and N, so we know the process, right? Once we know N equals P times Q, then we know phi N.
So from phi N we choose E, then we are able to calculate D easily.
So D is a private key.
So this process is not difficult. So once you have very large P and Q, two prime numbers,
then you can follow this process to generate the public key and the private key.
It is also computationally easy for sender A knowing the public key and the message to be encrypted to generate the corresponding subtext.
So C equals M to the E mod N. This is not that difficult.
And also for the receiver B to do the decryption, this process is not difficult.
So that means to calculate M equals C to the D mod N, well, this is computationally achievable.
However, it is computationally infeasible that for an adversary knowing the public key from E and N to determine the private key,
this is infeasible.
Well, the only way is to derive the private key is you should guess N equals the product of P and Q.
How to get this P and Q? Well, this is infeasible at this moment.
So we can choose P and Q to be very large.
And also for an adversary, it is computationally infeasible from public key and subtext
to recover the original message M.
Because original message M equals C to the D mod N. Without this D, you cannot derive the original message M.
Without D, you cannot get the original message M.
Well, in the public key scheme, the two keys can be applied in other order.
Well, we can do the encryption like M to the D mod N or M to the C mod N.
So the second line means we want to achieve secrecy, confidentiality.
Secrecy. The first line means we want to achieve the signature authentication.
Use your private key where you can generate your signature.
Use your public key where you can conceal your message M.
So in this design, in this RSA algorithm, we call it.
So in this RSA algorithm, in the encryption-decryption process, we say, well, in fact, it provides some trapped one-way function.
First, we look at the meaning of one-way function.
So a one-way function means this function maps a domain into a range.
So from domain X, capital X, to a range Y. So that means it defines a mapping.
A mapping from X to Y.
This is a function. A mapping from X to Y.
So this function, given an input, given an input X belong to X.
So FX equals some Y. And this small y belong to the range.
From an X, we have a unique Y.
So this one-way means, well, from X to Y, it is this direction. It is easy.
From X, given the input, we follow the function calculation. We get a Y. It is easy.
However, the inverse way is impossible.
So from Y to get the original X, this is infeasible. Not possible.
So we can see for the hash function, like the MD5, the SHA256.
From the input X to the SHA256, with input X, we get its output, H.
This is easy. However, from H, if we want to guess what's the original input X, this is not possible.
Well, based on the one-way function, we have the trapdoor one-way function.
The trapdoor one-way function is a family of invertible function FK.
Such that, well, with a K and with X input, we calculate the Y. It is easy.
And also, with Y and the K, we get its inverse, reverse way. In the reverse way, we get original X. It is also easy.
However, if we don't know the K, well, to calculate the original input X, it is infeasible.
So that means just like in our RSA algorithm, we have from, well, with the original message M,
and we use the public key E, we use public key E, we mod N, we get the C. So this is easy.
We see C is Y, right? And once we have the D, we mod N, we get M. This is easy.
However, without D, we send N to get M and no D, this is impossible.
That means the D is a key K here. No D to get back the original message M, this is infeasible.
So that means a practical public key scheme depends on a suitable trapdoor one-way function.
We should have the public key to do the decryption such that we can get the original message M from the self-text C.
Okay, we can see for the RSA algorithm, before the application of the public key crypto system, each participant must generate a pair of keys.
This pair of keys is E and D, right? E is a public key, D is a corresponding private key.
To generate E and D, first we should choose two prime numbers, P and Q, secretly.
You cannot disclose these two big numbers, otherwise people will generate your private key easily.
So once you choose P and Q, normally you will select E and then you will calculate D as your private key.
So because the value N equals P times Q will be, this N will be known to any potential adversary.
The primes must be chosen from a sufficiently large set. So primes P, Q, you should choose these two to be very large, right?
Okay, the method used for finding large primes, well, this method should be reasonably efficient.
To attack the RSA algorithm, we called this problem is a factoring problem.
The reason is because once you can factor N into its two prime factors P and Q, so once you can get N equals P times Q,
then you will be able to calculate its corresponding potential function phi, right?
Once you can do that factorization, just like suppose N equals 1, 1, 9, so what's P and Q?
P equals Q equals
Okay, 7, 17, right? So then, well, because this number is very small, right?
You can do the factorization quickly and then you'll be able to calculate the phi to be 96, right?
In our previous example, and then you will be able to suppose E is any number.
Can E be like, suppose E is 7, right?
Can we choose E to be 10?
Not possible, why not?
Not really prime to phi, right?
So when you guarantee that DCT E and phi should be 1, so this one is not okay.
Saving is fine. Well, given we know phi N, we know E, we will be able to generate the D.
So D equals actually is coming to
So D is E must 1 mod phi N.
To get the modular inverse value, we can use the extended Euclidean algorithm, but we can quickly calculate D from E and phi.
So once we can do the factorization problem, we can solve the factorization of N and E is null.
So we will be able to calculate the private key D.
And we can see the history to do this factorization problem, the challenge.
In December 2000 online, well, we can factor rising the N.
So this N is the number of bits.
To be 768 bits, corresponds to the number of decimal digits to be 232 decimal digits.
The recent progress is in 2020.
Well, a group of people showed that we are able to factorize big N with the 829 bits.
The length for N to be over 800 is not secure anymore.
So it is suggested that we should at least choose the N to be 1 or 24 bits today.
Or to be more secure, to be 2 or 48 bits.
For your N to generate your public key and private key in your application.
Okay, so let's have an overview about the encryption.
So we can use either the symmetric encryption.
So symmetric encryption means we assume we can achieve confidentiality.
That means the message will be kept to be a secret.
Will only be known by the sender and the receiver.
Because both the sender and the receiver, they have the key K.
And this key K can be used in both the encryption and the decryption algorithm, like the AES algorithm.
So in this symmetric scheme, we can achieve the message confidentiality.
Not known by others.
So the message cannot be known by others.
If we apply the public key encryption,
Once we use the public key of the receiver B,
And then we can achieve the message confidentiality.
The reason is because only the receiver can do the decryption.
Or we can use AES public key to do the encryption.
Then we can generate the signature along with the message.
So this signature will be verified by the receiver B.
So B will use the sender's public key for verification.
So B as the receiver will guarantee that the message is really from Alice.
Because the B is using Alice's public key to do the decryption.
Of course, we can use both the private key and public key at both the sender side and the receiver side.
So private key for signature generation and public key for the message confidentiality.
To achieve message confidentiality, to guarantee the message is encrypted and not known by others.
So in the decryption side, the receiver side, we can do the decryption.
First use the receiver's private key to do the decryption and then to do the verification.
So public key of Alice to do the signature verification.
Authentication and signature actually should be the same meaning.
We verify your signature will guarantee this real sender.
So we guarantee this real sender.
The real sender means this authentication will authorize.
You're authorized because you can provide a correct signature.
So then we finish our lecture three.
And we have the TECOM exercises for your practice.
So exercise four is for RSA and exercise five is for Diffie-Hellman algorithm.
OK, so we finish and let's have a stop, have a break, 10 minutes.
OK, then after break, we continue with lecture four.
Thank you.