Okay, it's very good that some of you have some questions and that shows you're thinking
you will try to answer more from the slides.
That's very good.
Okay, let's continue with our lecture 6.
So lecture 6 is about another protocol for ePayment, it is 3D.
So this one is still used today.
And let's see how it works, the 3D protocol.
Okay, so 3D protocol is very useful, still used today to support today's online transaction,
right?
Online shopping, so Steve Jobs will say, you see, our smartphone is so secure because we
have this 3D secure protocol.
Okay, so one case is just like today, if you go online shopping, and suppose you have the
online shopping, just like you're doing the online shopping through your desktop, then
your desktop, there will be a proper window to ask you to input some one-time password.
So we call this one is a PIN number, this one-time password will be sent to your smartphone
independently.
Okay, you have your smartphone, and today we assume your smartphone, just your personal
belongings will not be stolen by someone else.
You have your smartphone, because that smartphone, the smartphone number is registered to your
credit card company.
So credit card company will send this PIN number separately, okay?
And once you have this PIN number, you can input the PIN number into this proper window
to finish this payment process.
So this is required, if you cannot provide this password, then your transaction cannot
be approved.
And today it is still used, it is very efficient and very secure, and we say, well, it is very
useful, so we'll try to understand what's behind it, what's the logic, why it can provide
the security here.
The 3D secure is a solution that Visa introduced in 2001 to prevent three main sources of fraud
in the credit card online transaction.
For example, well, someone may use an unauthenticated card, well, you will have unauthenticated cards,
you cannot pass this 3D secure protocol, or your card has been stolen, but someone else
will try to use your credit card to do the online shopping, or some ASICL merchant may
make some fraudulent claims.
So all this kind of fraudulence can be prevented if we have this 3D secure protocols in the
online shopping.
The goal is to facilitate remote card payments, just like we have in online shopping.
The solution requires users to register, you should first register with your credit card,
your credit card company will register, your account, your card can support this 3D protocols.
And also in the payment process, it establishes a PIN number with their card issuer for authentication
during an online transaction.
We call it to be 3D, 3D means we have three domains.
We have the issuer domain, acquired domain, and in between we have the interoperability
domain through the Visa payment networks.
So within the issuer domain, we have the access control server.
So this server is maintained by the card issuer, the issuer bank, to support the card authentication.
And also we have the Visa directory, so this directory you can treat this one to be a server.
This server resides in the middle domain.
So this middle domain means the interoperability domain, and it mediates the communication
between the merchant and the issuer.
Okay, we look at the architecture for this 3D, 3D, three domains.
We have issuer domain, so you're the card holder, we have the issuer bank here, right?
So this is one domain.
The second domain is acquired domain, acquired domain, we have the merchant, we have the
acquired bank, that's a merchant's bank.
In between these two domains, we have some interoperability domain.
It includes the Visa directory.
This is a server.
This is server.
So this server, the main function is to check whether your card is valid.
So for these three domains, their communication will use the SSL communications.
So SSL is a secure socket layer, secure socket layer.
And TLS is transport layer security.
Well, in this architecture, we have five point-to-point SSL connections to connect the buyer, the
merchant, and the access control server for their secure communications, just like we
We can use your public key to negotiate, or session, secret key, right, or key K, to
be used for the future session, secure communications, use your public key scheme.
So later on, there could be multiple rounds, so we can talk secretly by using that secret
key K.
So this can be done in the SSL, this connection.
For these five point-to-point connections, the first one is from cardholder between the
cardholder and the merchant.
So this first one between the cardholder and the merchant.
In this connection, for example, the cardholder can place the order information.
We want to order a TV from this merchant, right?
And second connection is between the merchant and the visa directory.
You can see this number two.
Merchant will talk with the visa directory.
When you place your order, you will also provide your account information, your credit card
number.
So this credit card number will be obtained by merchant.
So merchant will talk with the visa directory to say, well, how about, is this card account
valid or number valid?
So the merchant will talk with the visa directory whether your card number is valid.
If it is valid, the visa directory, this server, will have another connection, another communication
channel with ACS.
So ACS is the access control server reside at the issuer bank, just like your credit
card company.
And the visa directory will construct this SSL connection with ACS to check whether your
card support, your card number, this card support 3D services.
Once the visa directory gets your credit card number, he will contact your visa company
or your master card company to check whether this one can be done in 3D protocols.
If it can be done in 3D protocols, then he will continue to forward the message through
this connection.
So message will be sent back to the card holder, just like you need to input a PIN number.
So the message will be go through from the merchant, sent to the card holder, just like
in this online shopping, there will be a pop-up window to ask you to input your PIN number.
That PIN number, that message will be sent to another connection between the card holder
and the access control server.
Your PIN number will be checked by the access server.
So this PIN number actually will be given to your smartphone from the issuer bank.
So issuer bank will deliver the PIN to your smartphone.
And you can get this PIN number from your smartphone and input this PIN number into
the pop-up window in your webpage to finish this transaction.
So this PIN number finally will arrive at the access server.
So access server of course knows the PIN number.
So we double check this PIN number is correct.
If it is correct, the issuer bank will have another connection with the merchant.
So from the issuer bank and the message will be sent to the merchant to notify this transaction
is approved, approval.
This transaction is approved from the issuer bank will notify the merchant that well this
transaction is approved.
So in this approved information, it contains some token.
So this token of course contains the issuer bank's signature and also contains just like
how much for this transaction.
And later on, the merchant can use this token to claim the credit from his bank.
The same idea, right?
So you can see, well, we have five connections.
Number one is between the merchant, between the cardholder and the merchant.
That's all the information, card information.
Number two is between the Visa directory and the merchant will check whether this credit
card number is valid.
Number three is here.
This is number four.
This is number three.
Between the cardholder and the access control server, the cardholder will provide a valid
PIN and this PIN information will be sent to the access server.
And number four is between the Visa directory and the access control server.
So this communication will answer whether the card can support 3D protocols.
And number five is between the merchant and access control server.
That means the issuer bank will finally notify the merchant whether this transaction is approved
or not.
So this is number five.
And the use of SSAL provides the service of confidentiality because all the messages will
be encrypted.
As we said before, the secret key, K, will be used to encrypt the message.
This key, K, for the encryption will be used for encryption and only that two participants
in the SSAL channel can know the key, K.
Of course, we will guarantee the integrity.
So the message integrity and authentication will be guaranteed by the signature.
We verify your signature.
We check your signature validity, we guarantee that this is really from us, not from Bob,
and also the message is not modified.
So before the 3D protocols, both the issuer and the acquired banks provide their bank
identification numbers and the URL addresses of their respective servers.
This URL is required because the message just like from the merchant sent to cardholder
and that message should contain the access information because later on the cardholder
need to forward the PIN number to that access address.
So both servers need to provide their URL information such that others can contact
your server.
So cardholder authentication mechanism is left to the issuer, cardholder can provide
the PIN number.
So today should be a PIN, right?
Or you can use your biometric just like your facial recognition, your smartphone sometimes
can recognize your face, your facial recognition or in some cases your fingerprint can do the
authentication purpose or you need to use your PIN number.
The default is a password that the user chooses as enrollment or we can use one-time password
to your smartphone today.
So now we look at in a 3D protocols, in a purchase, in a payment, what are the steps
there?
So very important we should have the payment authentication, well you can see we list totally
from step one to step twelve.
So let's see in each step what happens.
So first step, step one is the buyer should first indicate an intention to buy by clicking
on the corresponding buy button.
Step one means the cardholder will place the purchase order and the payment information,
right?
Will place the order information and transmit the payment information to the merchant.
That's step one, step one, sending your card information to the merchant.
And then in step two, in step two, the merchant's plug-in MPI, just like the merchant server,
request the list of participating card ranges from the Visa's 3D security directory with
the card range request message.
So step two is, okay, the merchant want to know whether this credit card number is valid
or not.
The merchant in step two is from here, in step two, the merchant wants to know whether
the account provided by the cardholder is valid or not, the credit card number account
valid or not.
So this Visa directory server will check the provided credit card number is valid or not
and give the response to the merchant server.
So that's step three.
So step three is a credit card card range response.
So in step two, the Visa directory will verify the PAN number provided by the customer is
within the range of participating cards.
So your account is valid.
Then in step three, the directory response is in the message card range response.
So step three is to reply the server, the merchant server, that this credit card is
valid.
Then in step four, the MPI, the server, the merchant server sends the verify enrollment
request message to the Visa directory to determine if 3D service is available for this number.
So step four and five.
So step four is this PAN number support 3D in this request.
Step four.
Of course, the server may need to contact the Israel Bank in the ACS.
The Israel Bank has this access control server, so this question will be forwarded to the
Israel Bank's access control server in step five.
And then if the credit card, just like your Visa card, can support this 3D protocols,
then the ACS server will reply a message in step six by giving this VES, VEE response.
So VEE means Verify Enrollment Response.
The VEE response message from the access control server of the Israel Bank indicates whether
the holder is registered in a 3D secure program.
So it contains the URL address.
This is the ACS address.
Toward this ACS server, the card holder browser will post the data.
So later on, the card holder browser, you're the card holder.
You need to input your PIN number, right?
In this browser, you can input your PIN number.
And this PIN number will be sent to this URL address.
So in step seven, you see, just like the merchant will get the response that this card number
support 3D service.
Then in step eight, the NPI sends a payer authentication request to the Israel Access
Control Server using the URL obtained in step seven.
So the information may appear to the buyer in a secondary pop-up window.
And then in step eight, the Israel Access Control Server establishes an SSL session
terminal and display the details of the transaction.
So in this step eight, between the card holder, because in a message in step eight, the message
will be sent from the merchant to the card holder in your online shopping, internet browser.
This browser will get the address of your access.
So in this pop-up window, there'll be a PIN number to also to input.
So this PIN information will be sent to the access server or the message will be exchanged
in the SSL connections.
So that's a job in the step eight.
So this will implement the authentication function, ask the holder for an identifier
can be a PIN or through biometric means, just like your fingerprint, your face, your facial
recognition for approval of the purchase.
So this access links the PIN request with a VE response message, because previously
in step seven, in step six, the merchant wants to know whether this card supports 3D, right?
If it supports 3D, then a message will be sent to the card holder asking you to input
the PIN.
So finally, in this request, you need to, as a customer, you need to input your PIN.
This PIN number will be sent to the access.
So after the holder has been authenticated, the access builds a card holder authentication
verification value of 20 octets.
And then this message will be sent back to the merchant in the step line.
So the CFVV is sent to the MPI merchant in the Payer Authentication Response message
is self-signed with the issuer's signature key.
So this one contains the issuer's signature key.
You can regard this one to be a token will be sent back to the merchant.
It contains the approval from the issuer bank.
So step line is the approval information.
In step line, the merchant finally will get the token CAV information, right?
How much the transaction, and also it contains the issuer bank's signature.
And later on, in step 10-12, step 10-11, that's archival purpose.
So that means this Payer Authentication Transaction request will be recorded in this authentication
HATERY server for archival purpose, just to have a block have some HATERY of this transaction.
And this is a response in step 11.
So step 10-12, we have a transaction PA, the payment authentication.
So PA means Payer Authentication Request.
We have the Payer Authentication Transaction Request.
This just like we have a record in your ACS server to have the HATERY.
The response is sent to the authentication HATERY server for archival within the Payer
Authentication Transaction Request message in step 10.
So step 11, just to response you, well, this message has been written into the block like
that.
It is successful.
This is the confirmation of the archival in step 11.
And step 12, for the merchant to get the credit, the merchant server verifies the signature
just like in the CVV, this message, before he or she submits a settlement required to
the acquired bank.
In step 12, the merchant can make a capture request.
So step 12 is to claim credit by the merchant.
Merchant now has the token from the issuer bank.
So this is step 12 for merchant to get credit.
So finally, the merchant can have his bank account with some balance increased because
of this transaction.
We do not have very detailed message structure.
No, we don't need to repeat those detailed structure.
Just to give you some idea, what's the whole logic, how many steps involved, and what's
the role for each participant.
So for security purpose, they need to communicate and to get what kind of information or verification
to do authentication.
So most important part is to guarantee that your credit card can support this service.
And then in your online shopping browser, there will be a purple window also to input
to authenticate this request.
Either you can do the authentication through a fingerprint, your face recognition, or you
need to input the PIN number.
So this PIN number will be sent from your issuer bank to your smartphone in a different
channel.
So in this way, we'll guarantee that you're the real customer to who has initiated, who
has launched this transaction, launched this transaction request.
So this is the whole process.
Any part not clear?
Also to the authentication, we have the signature checking.
And here besides the signature, we have the PIN number.
PIN number is sent to your smartphone.
This can be regarded as a double checking, okay?
Basically in the 3D protocols, it can be categorized to four phases.
The first one is step two or three, we update of the merchant's cash with a range of value
accounts.
Well, so just like this communication between the merchant and the VISA directory, in step
two and step three, the merchant will know whether this credit card is valid or not.
And then in step one, we have the customer to provide his card number.
And in step four, seven, we'll do the verification with this card number to support 3D service.
And then in step eight, this is the most important part to provide the PIN number to do the authentication.
Double check, you should have this PIN number through your smartphone, right?
To input this PIN number to finish this online transaction.
In step nine, it is a verification of the integrity of the payment information with
a signature of the issuer.
So this is the approval.
Your PIN number is correct and your issuer bank will approve, authorize this transaction
request.
The step 10 to 11 is for the purpose of the authentication attempts.
So step 12 is for a credit claim by the merchant.
So this is a rough classification of all steps into four phases.
Well, you can see here the table shows four different messages.
It involves which participants and what's the direction, right?
First one is for credit card request from merchant to VITA directory.
And we see from here the purchase request, the payer authentication authorization request,
this from merchant to the issuer, and this message will go through the card holder's
So encoded request to authenticate the payer protected against inadvertent change by the
browser.
So at this step, you should provide your PIN number.
Another one I want to mention here is about the PA response.
This is from issuer to the merchant and also via card holder browser.
So this is a response to the PA request sent by the issuer access control server.
It contains the CAV information and also just as some token indicating the transaction amount
and also contains the ACS signature.
Okay, so here I finished the discussion about the 3D protocols.
So you should be clear about this figure, three domains, and we have totally like 12
steps.
So what's the purpose for each step?
What kind of function provided in each step and how this one can provide security, right?
This one can provide the authentication, it's different from the, what's the difference
between this one and the previous set protocols.
Okay, so I stop here and today we still have the lab.
So we have a five-minute break for the TA to set up the presentation.
So I will still be here, if you have any question, you can ask me, thank you.