Okay, let's continue with our second part of today's lecture.
Now we go to our lecture for about digital signature.
We mentioned that the public scheme can be used to signature generation.
So signature can be used for authentication.
That's very important, right?
When you do the online shopping, the server, your critical server will guarantee you're the real one to do the online shopping.
So this process is called authentication.
Authentication is satisfied.
Then your critical company will authorize that transaction, that payment request.
Then you can continue with the online payment.
Otherwise, your payment request will be denied.
So authentication is very important.
How can we do the authentication?
That means you should generate a valid signature.
Okay, first we look at part one about signature generation and verification.
And we use the RSA algorithm for this explanation.
So we have the authentication problem just like in the internet.
Suppose Bob gets a message from Alice.
Well, Bob will ask whether he can trust this information.
Is this information really from Alice?
Just like Alice sent a payment request to Bob, asked Bob to authorize that payment request, right?
So then Bob needs to guarantee this is a real request from Alice.
Otherwise, Bob cannot approve that request.
However, you know, in the internet, a message can be modified by others.
So how can you guarantee, well, the message is not modified?
Or the message is not fabricated by someone else?
Just that the message is not from someone else, if...
This is not a message from Alice, but from if, right?
How can you prevent this case to happen?
Well, then we need to use the digital signature.
And suppose we have an electronic document to be sent from Alice to Bob.
The question is, is there a functional equivalent to a handwritten signature?
And this signature is easy for Alice to sign on the document, but hard for anyone else to forge.
The Alice signature, and also it is easy for Bob or anyone else to verify.
Well, this is really the signature from Alice.
And today we have the solution.
This is a digital signature.
And we use Alice, the private key, to generate the digital signature.
And anyone else can use Alice's public key to do the signature verification.
So we verify the signature by using Alice's public key.
Oh, well, this is a process, just like you have a message, then you can use your private key.
To generate the signature, and this signature will be sent to the receiver.
At the receiver side, well, the receiver will get the message and also the signature.
So the receiver will use the sender's public key to do the verification.
So the receiver will check whether this signature equals what.
Equals M to D. Is this a verification?
Yes or no?
So to do the verification, we have the words here.
We should use the public key, not private key, right?
Because the receiver has no idea about the D.
So this is not right.
We should use the public key.
So how can we use public key?
Because according to the RSA algorithm, S to the E equals M to the E to the D, right?
Because, you see, S equals M to the D.
So S to E equals M to the E to the D.
This is congruent to M mod M.
So that means in the verification, we have the signature.
We apply the public key here, E, and we will do this calculation.
Whether S to the E mod M equals the message M.
M is here.
If this equation is true, we say it is valid.
This is a valid signature.
Otherwise, we say the signature is not correct.
Is that clear?
So one example here is Alice sent the message, hello Bob, to Bob.
Alice wants to sign this message by using her private key.
Well, this is a message M, and this part is a signature S.
So S equals M to the D mod M, okay?
So both message and signature will be received by Bob.
So Bob will use Alice's private key to do the verification.
So the verification process is, well, S to the E.
Well, this S to the E equals M D to the E.
This is M E D.
This is congruent to M mod M, right?
Well, if this equation is correct, then Bob can guarantee that the message is really from Alice.
Okay, so because Bob will use Alice's private key, this one, to do the verification.
So in this way, Bob can verify that Alice sent the message, and that the message has not been modified.
Well, if the message is modified to be another one, if M becomes M prime, then will this M prime,
this M prime,
the from S to the E, we only get M.
So this M does not equal to M prime.
But so that means, well, the message cannot be modified in this because we have both the message
and signature.
From signature, we only get M but not M prime.
In other words, if the Bob got M prime and S, so Bob will verify S to the E mod M,
then Bob will get M.
So this M does not equal to M prime here.
So Bob will know the message has been modified.
Is that clear?
Well, in a generic model, we should follow this procedure.
Well, the original message supports the sender is Bob, Alice is the receiver.
The message first will apply the hash function.
No matter
we've run into a server error, some function might not work right now.
Yeah.
Well, in this generic model, the message first will go through a hash function.
No matter how large of the original message of the hash function we have,
we have a fixed output, the hash result.
So normally the hash result can be just like, if you apply the SHA 256 of original message M,
you will get this edge.
So this edge is 256 bits long.
256 bits means, well, this edge is 32 bytes.
So no matter how large of your original message, you will have this edge result
of a hash function.
The output will be 32 bytes.
So then you will do your signature based on this hash result.
So this is hash of M and you will generate your signature based on this hash result.
That means your S equals your hash result.
Suppose we're using the RSA algorithm.
So this one, we apply the private key to generate the signature.
The original message M and S, the signature will be sent to Alice.
So this is M plus S will be sent to Alice.
So Alice will obtain both M and S. Alice will apply the same hash function.
So M, after the hash function, we have the same output, H.
Suppose this M is not modified.
So this output is H, M.
Small h equals this one, right?
This H, M, we can apply.
This H, M, based on the S message, we can apply the public key.
Bob's public key, so S, signature will apply the public key E.
This equals H, M, D, E again.
So this is H, M, E, D.
Mod M, well, E, D can be cancelled.
This is H, M.
So the result here is H, M.
We will compare these two, whether these two are the same or not.
If they are the same, that means the message and the signature are both correct.
And this is a normal procedure for signature generation and verification.
Any questions?
Well, we can see using this digital signature,
we can provide authentication of digital messages or documents.
Well, the signature, because the signature, we use your public key to do the verification.
We use
Alice public key in verification.
So we say this message is really from Alice.
This is the meaning of authentication.
The request is really from Alice.
And also, it provides long repudiation.
So long repudiation means the signer, just like Alice,
cannot successfully claim she did not send a message while also claiming her private key
remains secret.
So either your private key is lost, someone else has your private key and can fabricate
your signature.
Or if your secret key is secure, then your signature must be signed by you.
You cannot deny your signature.
So long repudiation means you can't
deny the message is sent from you.
Okay.
Otherwise, on this, well, you say your secret, your secret key is lost.
And also we say the digital signature provides integrity.
So integrity means M is not modified.
M is not modified.
Well, if a message is digitally sent, any change in the message of the signature invalidates
the signature.
The reason is because M will be sent along with your signature.
Okay.
And your signature equals the hash result of M
to the private key.
So S equals the hash result to your private key mod M.
Well, if you have another M prime with this signature,
well, if you have another M prime with this signature,
it's about M is modified to be M prime.
Then you apply S to the E mod M and this will generate the HM.
So this, this HM does not equal to HM prime.
But in other words, well, once you have a correct signature S, this will guarantee your
message M is not modified.
Otherwise, it cannot pass the signature verification process, right?
Only the correct M can match your signature.
Okay.
Now we look at the RSA, the signature scheme.
We said that RSA algorithm can be applied to encryption, decryption, key exchange, and
also to be applied in this signature generation.
In the setup, just like in the RSA algorithm, we have the add-on, add-on, add-on, add-on,
just like in the RSA algorithm, we have the N to be the product of two prime numbers.
So PQR large primes will each to be 124 bits long.
And we choose the E, then we can generate the private key to be D.
D will be used in the signing process.
And public key EN will be used for the signature verification.
So in signature generation, we apply the message M.
At this moment, we don't consider the hash function, okay?
So M to D mod N, it is the signature S.
So we say S is the generated signature for the message M.
So M is the message to be signed.
In the verification, we apply the public key to the S mod N.
Then we calculate whether the result equals M or not.
If it equals, we say the signature is valid.
Otherwise, we output invalid signature.
Okay, now we look at this example.
Suppose we choose two primes, P to be 47 and Q to be 71.
So N equals P times Q equals 3337.
We choose E such that it is relative prime to phi.
So phi equals P minus 1 times Q minus 1.
So this is 3220.
Suppose we choose E to be plus 1019.
Then we compute the private key D using the extended Euclidean algorithm.
So D can be calculated to be 79.
So public key, in this example, it is E and N.
E is 101 line.
N is 3337.
The private key is 79.
So in this example, suppose the message is 688.
So signature can be generated by the M to the D mod N.
This is 1570 to be a signature.
The message and signature will be sent to the receiver.
So receiver will do the verification and receiver will check if
S to the public key E mod N equals the message itself or not.
So of course, well, S to E should equal M itself, right?
In the RSA algorithm, we choose E, D such that M, E, D mod N equals M itself.
So this makes them to generate the public key and private key.
And because of this property, we guarantee in this signature verification process,
S to the E mod N, it is, it equals M.
Okay, in this exercise, suppose we use some small number and also to redo the previous example.
From E, well, equal three is small number and first step, you should calculate
the private key D, right?
From private key D, the signature equals M to the D mod N.
Then you'll check whether M equals S to the E mod N.
So three steps. First step, calculate the private key D.
Second step, to generate the signature. Third step, to do the signature verification.
Step one, step two, step three. So this is signature
generation.
This step three is signature
verification.
Okay, can you use probably five to 10 minutes to do this calculation?
Okay, some of you have finished
the calculation step one, right? To get the private key D. Well, the D, what's the D value?
D equals two, one, four, seven, right?
Well, in this example, because the public key E is three and the N is
three, three, three, seven. Five N is
three, two, two, zero.
So five N is here, is two, three thousand, two hundred and twenty.
Well, because E is a small data, in fact, we can calculate. What we know is
E times D equals K times five N plus one, is that right? Because E D
is coming to one, mod five.
Mod five. So in other words, we calculate D equals
K times five N plus one divided by E. Here E is small number equals three.
K times five N is three, two, two, zero plus one.
So you can try K equals one. If K equals one, well, D is not an integer. How about
K equals two? If K equals two, we get D to be two times three, two, two, zero plus one
divided by three. This equals two one forty seven.
OK, so this way is also fine. You don't need to apply the extended Euclidean algorithm.
Of course, because E is small, applying the extended Euclidean algorithm is also
very fast. But when E is five, three, so you can apply this method.
OK, the first step, we get the private key D to be two thousand and two thousand one hundred
and four seven, this large number. For the second step, well, we want to calculate the signature.
So S equals M is.
So M is six hundred and eighty eight.
To the two one four seven mod N, N is three three three seven. Of course, this is a
big number. So if it is very big,
well, in fact, you still can solve it. So how to solve it? You can use the CRT, right?
CRT, that means because N is three three three seven equals P is forty seven times seventy one.
So that means you want to suppose this is big number. This one, we use this one to be
a big number T. So we want to calculate T mod, this P, this Q, P, this is S1,
T mod Q is S2. For S1, S2, we will be able to generate S quickly. So in fact, T mod
P, this equals six hundred and eighty eight to the two one forty seven mod P,
forty seven. So in fact, this is not that difficult. Well, you can do some calculation to get the
remainder forty seven. This is fourteen times forty seven plus thirty. In the exponent part,
you should have forty six times forty six plus
thirty one mod forty seven. OK, so this part is zero. This part can be canceled.
This is congruent to thirty to the thirty one mod forty seven. So this number is not that large.
Of course, you can make it to be smaller to do some factorization.
If this one is too big, right, you can factorize it. You can represent it to be like thirty
to the five to six times thirty mod forty seven. You can first calculate the inside.
So this one is thirteen. Thirty to the fifth mod forty seven is thirteen. Thirteen to the sixth
times thirty. This is congruent to forty three mod forty seven. So we have S1 to be forty three.
Forty three.
OK, step by step, use your calculator or use your computer. You will be able to get S1.
And similarly, you can get S2.
P is seventy one.
So seventy one.
OK, well, you can apply the same idea as we calculate S1. You will get S2. I give you the result
directly to be here to be sixteen. So you have S2 to be sixteen.
Mod Q is sixteen. Well, so we can let
from this equation, we let S equals
Q is seventy one times small t.
We use x plus sixteen.
Because the S is small number, S mod Q, Q is seventy one
equals sixteen. So S can be represented as seventy one times x plus sixteen.
So we substitute this one to be the first equation. So in other words, seventy one x
sixteen mod forty three. No, mod P is forty seven equals forty three.
OK, this equation you can get, you can derive from seventy one, you get twenty four.
OK, you can derive twenty four t is congruent to twenty seven mod forty seven.
So now you can try, because now the number is not very large, you can try t equals one, two, three.
Each one can satisfy this equation until you can try the result is seven.
The result is seven. So seven times twenty four mod forty seven equals twenty seven.
So that means here is not x, here should be x. Anyway, we translate here to be t.
So t can be seven. In other words, this t can meet, satisfy this equation. OK, and then we let t to be seven.
So this will derive t equals seven. S equals seventy one times seven or sixteen. This is the signature.
So signature is five one three.
Or in step three, it is quite easy because well, you apply the s to the e. This is five one three to the three to start.
Mod mod and this, of course, will equal the message itself.
Well, here I write all the procedure. Well, to show that how you can use different method to calculate the private key d in the step one.
OK, if e, if the given public key e is small, then you can use that equation to calculate the private key d.
Otherwise, you should use the extended Euclidean algorithm to calculate the module inverse.
Then in step two, to generate the signature, you can apply the Chinese remainder theorem.
So here the data is quite large. Well, in your midterm test, I will try to make the number to be small.
Don't need to worry. However, you need to guarantee you need to master this CRT technique to, well, to apply this CRT process to generate the result.
Like here. So that means just like in this example, this big number mod n can be translated to big number mod p.
We have s1, big number mod q. We have s2. Then from these two equations, we can calculate the original small s.
Well, in RSA algorithm, the key length actually is critical for the security purpose.
RSA algorithm is not efficient because it gains strength slowly. The RSA, when we choose n,
the length to be 1024 bits, the security is equivalent to an 80-bit symmetry key, just like in the AES.
In the AES, the key length will to be 80 bits, and AES can achieve the same security level as RSA.
When we use the RSA, the key length to be 1024 bits.
And if we increase the n to be 248 bits, this is equivalent to a 112-bit key.
So of course, this is not AES. AES requires the key length to be much longer.
So we can continue to increase the RSA key length. But you can see, well, when we apply the symmetry key,
that's much more efficient. When the large size n to be applied in RSA, the performance is terrible.
Because n is very large, you need to do the exponential operation and mod n. That's terrible.
So because the computation time required for large keys increases rapidly,
well, if we increase the key length from 124 to 248, the key length doubled.
But the operation is eight times. Eight times. The reason is because you can see
message to the e mod n. When this n doubled, your e, your n message to the e mod this n.
This calculation will be eight times.
Compared to, well, let's just half the key length. So that means, well, RSA, the algorithm can be
used in very limited cases. For the large document encryption-decryption, we should use the
symmetry key scheme. But we can use RSA for the key distribution. Is that clear?
The key can be large. Well, we use RSA to encrypt that key. That key can be sent to the
receiver. And then both sender and receiver can use that key to encrypt a large file.
Okay. Today I stop here. Well, today we still have the project introduction. So let's have
a break. After five minutes, we start with today's project introduction. Thank you.