Okay, good evening.
So let's start with today's lecture.
Today we will continue with our lecture three about cryptography.
Last time we talked about the number theory, right?
So we know like the Euler's theorem.
So today we will start with like the symmetric encryption.
So part one is about the symmetric encryption, part two is about isometric encryption, that's
a public key scheme.
Public key scheme, public encryption is based on the number theory.
So from the Euler's theorem, we will have today's RSA algorithm.
Today, first, we look at the part one about symmetric encryption.
Here is the diagram to show that in the symmetric encryption, we have the plaintext as an input
and as output, we also want to get the plaintext, the same plaintext.
So at the left hand side, we say we have the sender, right hand side, we have the receiver.
In the middle, we have a channel and we assume that the channel may not be reliable.
So in the channel, we want to send the transmitted self-text.
This self-text should be encrypted.
In this symmetric encryption, the plaintext, we denote the plaintext to be x.
So x, we first go through an encryption algorithm.
For example, here is AES.
So AES is an advanced encryption standard.
When the x goes through this encryption algorithm, normally we will have a key k.
We can use this key k to encrypt the plaintext x.
Then we get the self-text y and y equals this function, encryption function, we call it the encryption function.
With the input to be x and the key k, so this key k is a secret.
At the receiver side, so this part is the sender side, this part is the receiver side.
And receiver will use the same key k to do the decryption.
And we have the decryption algorithm, that's the reverse process of the encryption algorithm.
So the AES, normally we have some character substitution, some shifting with some block replaced by another block.
So this kind of operations, based on the key k, we do shifting, do permutation.
So lots of steps to get to the subtext.
And then at the receiver side, we do the reverse process.
Once you have the key k, and then you can do the decryption.
So this decryption function is also known, that's the AES.
So both AES are in encryption, decryption, the process is publicly known.
Only the key k is the secret.
So once the receiver and the sender, they share the same key k, then the receiver can use the key k to do the decryption.
So the decryption function, we have two inputs, one is the key k, one is the subtext y.
So in the decryption, we can get the original plaintext x.
So this is the model for symmetry encryption and decryption.
The critical part here is you should have the symmetric key k to be obtained by both the sender and receiver.
Is that clear?
Well, in a symmetric server model, we have two requirements for secure use of conventional encryption.
First one is we should have a strong encryption algorithm.
So today we use AES.
So this one is believed to be very secure, very secure at this moment.
Okay, the second requirement is that the sender receiver must have obtained copies of the secret key k.
In a secure fashion, must keep the key secure.
If the key is not secure, anyone else has a key can do the decryption and will know your plaintext.
Okay, so this key k should be your secret, not known by others.
Oh, you can see, well, for this symmetry encryption, the key k, we should have some way to make sure the key k will be shared, will be obtained by both the sender and receiver.
Right.
So how to implement this secure channel for key distribution?
This one is a challenge.
So it is a challenge to distribute the key k to the receiver and to the sender.
Okay, so we'll see later how we can do the key distribution or the key to be obtained by both the sender and the receiver.
They can use some way, like to use the asymmetric encryption to attain this purpose.
Well, in the channel, for this channel, the channel part or the message will go through like the internet or the public transmission in the air.
Right. Today we have like 6G or the message from your smartphone to access point.
So between the access point and your smartphone, we regard this is a public channel and anyone can hear your transmitted message and your message can be analyzed by some attacker.
So those attackers, we call them to be the crypto analyst.
For attacker, they will try to decrypt your message.
Okay, so they will get your subtext.
However, the attacker has no idea of your private key.
So normally no key.
That means the attacker cannot get your plain text, cannot do the decryption.
That means the attacker will try to guess or attack your message to get the private key, the symmetric key with a key.
Then the crypto analyst will be able to generate the original plain text.
But this is difficult.
Okay, we'll make it to be difficult to be attacked for your subtext.
So we look at one example for the symmetry encryption.
And this one is called the Caesar cipher.
And this one is very famous.
It is the simplest and the earliest known use of substitution cipher.
And he said that this cipher is created by Julius Caesar to be used in the war against some of his enemies.
This cipher involves replacing each letter of the alphabet with a letter standing three places further down the alphabet.
And we assume that the alphabet is wrapped around so that the letter following z is a.
So wrap around means what?
Well, we can regard this one as a mod operation.
And totally we have 26 letters, right, characters.
So wrap around means we take the mod operation.
Suppose we have the original plain text to be meet me after the toga party.
Then the subtext will be for every letter with plus three.
So we plus three.
And after M, we have M.
And.
Oh, P.
So M plus three is P here, but M is P.
And similarly, every letter we count three positions further down will get a corresponding letter.
So E is H, E is H, T is W.
That means we have this lower line to be the subtext.
OK, very simple.
So, of course, your enemy obtained this sentence.
We have no idea about the original meaning of the sentence.
However, once we know it is a SIDA cipher to the decryption, it is not difficult.
The reason is because we can take the brute force attack.
So once we know, well, it is SIDA cipher, and then we can do the brute force attack and we can try different keys.
For example, if keys one from this subtext, this is subtext C.
That's a text.
If keys one, that means original data, the letter, we must one.
So from P, we have O, right?
From P, we have O, from H, we have G.
So this is the first trial for the key equals one.
Of course, this one, we have no idea about the original print text.
If we continue, the key equals two and key equals three, and then we can get the original print text.
Very easy to get the original print text.
Well, in this brute force attack, we can see, at most, we try 25 times, right?
Because we can list all possible cases.
The key can be from one to 25.
Totally, we have 26 characters.
So not many times can we find the print text in this brute force attack.
So in this SIDA cipher algorithm, we can define the transformation as from every letter,
we get several texts later, three positions later in the alphabet position.
So we can assign each letter a number, just A to be zero, B to be one, C to be two.
And this algorithm can be expressed as encryption.
The P's original print text, this three is a key.
So the encryption is P plus three mod 26.
So we get the subtext C here.
So of course, a shift, this example is three.
A shift can be of any amount.
So the general SIDA algorithm is for any key to be K.
So we have P plus K mod 26 to get the subtext C.
And this key K can take a value in the range from one to 25.
The decryption process is the reverse way.
The encryption is P plus three, so the decryption is minus three.
So this decryption is C minus K with mod 26.
Then we can get the original print text.
OK, this is quite simple.
So here is another example from the movie, The Imitation Game.
So this movie is about the story of the father of modern computer science, Alan Turing.
So in that movie, Turing gave his friend one subtext, W-I-I-C-S-Y, Mr. M-R.
So can I try to get the print text?
What's a print text? You can try.
What's a print text?
So what's the meaning of the first word?
C. Good.
So actually, you can try all the key K.
Well, you have K equals one.
So before W, we have U, V, W, right?
That's V. I is H. H. Well, this is not a word.
If K equals two, we have V. Before we had U, GG.
So K equals three, we have T, F, F. K equals four, we have S, E, E.
So easily, we find the key K to be four in this example.
So another very famous symmetry encryption is the technique called one-time pad.
So this one-time pad here, a pad actually contains the code to do the encryption and
decryption, this pad.
And this one-time pad is an improvement to the Verlamp Cypher and is proposed by an army
signal cop officer Joseph.
The key in this one-time pad is a random string that is a list as long as the print text.
So when you have a very long sentence, you have the same length of key to do the encryption
and to do the decryption.
Well, because it's a one-time pad and the string is totally random, and we require that
the key will not be repeated.
So each new message requires a new key.
So this one-time pad, this scheme is unbreakable.
The reason is because the self-text is a random output.
Because your key is totally random, this will make your self-text to be totally random.
The self-text contains no information whatsoever about the print text.
So this is the reason why we have no way to break the code.
So encryption, we use the one-time pad, the key.
So decryption, we use the same key.
This encryption is similar to the shift cypher.
So we look at the general form for this one-time pad and support that Zn is a set to represent
the alphabet.
So alphabet number from 0 to n must 1, n must 1.
And the print text space equals the self-text space, that's a key space.
That means, well, we can have, suppose the length of the print text is n, just like here.
And the print text, we have n characters.
The key, the same length, so key, we have same n keys.
The self-text can be the same length.
For the encryption, so every character is in this range from 0 to n must 1, n must 1.
So this m is the length of the print text.
Zn is every character belong to the Zn, that set.
For encryption, we can get the self-text yi to be xi plus ki.
We take mod m.
This is yi, because totally we have m, the number, to be the total number of alphabet.
So you can see, this is the encryption process for the given print text and the key.
For the decryption, that's a reverse part.
So reverse means, well, for every given yi, with minus ki, with mod m, then we can get
the print text xi.
So here you can see, the y2 minus k2, mod m, we get the original x2.
So this one is y2, OK?
So now we look at a particular case for the one-time pad.
It is a binary version.
So binary version means every code should be either 0 or 1, should be a bit with two
values, 0 or 1, and the key should be chosen randomly.
For example, if the print text is 1101, 1111, suppose we have a key, and this key is here.
Well, the key has the same length as the print text, and then we do the add operation, right?
We add them together, and well, m here is 2, because we have only two values for every
letter, for every character.
So we add them together, then we take the mod 2 operation, and we look at the subtext
should be 1 plus 0 is 1, 1 plus 1 is 2.
So 2 mod 2 is 0, right?
And then we have 1, 1, this is 0, 0, 1, 0.
OK, this is a subtext.
So from a subtext, how can we get the print text?
Here is plus, according to our previous slide operation, which was minus, right?
Minus here.
Then we use the same key k, 0, 1, 1, 0, 1, 0, 0, 1, with minus the key k, and then we
have the same mod 2 operation, mod 2.
OK, well, 1 minus 0 is 1, 0 minus 1 is 1, mod 2 is 1, 0 minus 1 is 1, 1 minus 2 is 1.
So 1, 1 is 0, 1 minus 0 is 1, 0 minus 1 is 1, 1 minus 0 is 1, oh sorry, this is 0 minus
0 is 0, 1 minus 0 is 1, 0 minus 1 is 1.
So this is exactly the original print text.
For bit operation, in fact, we have different functions available.
So for bit, we can do AND operation, this is AND, like 0 is 0, 0 and 1 is 0, 1, 0 is
0, 1, 1 is 1, and we have the bit operation to be OR, OR means either one is 1, then the
result will be 1.
And also we have the addition mod 2.
So this is also known as bit, exclusive OR operation.
Exclusive OR means the same will be 0, the different inputs will have the result to be 1.
And this is addition, just like previously, or subtraction mod 2, addition mod 2 is same
as exclusive OR operation.
So previously you can see we have addition mod 2, addition mod 2, and this subtraction
mod 2 is same as addition mod 2.
Now we have this question, can we use operators other than bit XOR for binary version of one-time
pad?
In other words, can we use the AND operation here for these two bit strings?
Yes or no?
So here, previously we used addition mod 2, right?
Addition mod 2 means exclusive OR, so how about can we use AND?
Yes or no?
Can we use AND to do the encryption?
No?
So we can try, right?
Just like the first four bits, 1, 1, 0, 1, 0, 1, 1, 0, we'll do AND operation.
If we have AND, that means both of them to be 1, the result is 1, otherwise the result
is 0.
So this 0, 1, 0, 0.
And for this one actually, even we have the key K, the key, this is the key, we will use
same key to be 0, 1, 1, 0, and how can we get back the original message?
If we take the AND operation again, this will get 0, 1, 0, 0.
So this one does not equal to the P, right?
So that means AND cannot be adopted in this kind of encryption and decryption.
And to the OR operation, so the answer here is no.
What we can do is we use the addition mod 2, just like the bit XOR in this encryption
and decryption.
That would be fine.
Otherwise, the answer would be no.
So one time part, why do we say it is perfect, it is the perfect solution?
So this one is perfect security.
The reason is because the key is totally random.
So we look at this example.
This is the subtext here.
We can have the exhaustive search of all possible keys, and it is possible that we can get many
legible plaintext.
So we have no way to know which one was intended plaintext.
So one example is we have this subtext.
And we'll suppose we have the key K, K1 to be here.
Your key K can be any characters, one time part, right?
The key will not be repeated, and you don't know what the key K is.
So the key K1 is here, then we have the plaintext to be this sentence.
The sentence has some meaning.
If we use another key K2, then we will get another plaintext P2.
So either P1, P2 actually, they contain some meaning.
So in this way, you can see, in fact, because the key can be totally random, and thus we
cannot know what's the original plaintext, unless you have the key K.
If you have the key K, then you will know what's the original plaintext.
However, one time part, we say it is a perfect solution.
However, in practice, when we apply this technique, it has two fundamental difficulties.
So there is a practical problem of making large quantities of random key.
This is the first difficulty, because if your original message is very long, you need to
generate the same length of the key.
So that means your key will be very long, and it can be millions of random characters
on a regular basis.
So this is difficult.
The first difficulty is to generate large quantities of random keys.
The second difficulty is, once you have the key, how can you send the key to the receiver?
So we call this one the key distribution problem.
You have the key, that's fine.
How can you let your receiver to have the same key as you?
So because of these difficulties, the one time part is of limited utility.
So to use primer relief for low bandwidth channels, that requires very high security.
So this key distribution problem is, you see, you will send the key to your receiver.
However, before the sending, you should send the key K to the receiver.
The key K has the same length as your plaintext.
If you can send the key K, why not directly send the plaintext P, right?
So we talked about the one time part.
The purpose is to let you know this one time part solution is the only crypto system that
exhibits perfect secrecy.
The only solution, that's AES, the submission encryption, the public key scheme, or those
or other cryptography, those schemes are not perfect, cannot provide perfect security.
So this is the only one that can show the perfect secrecy.
Okay, any questions?
So part one is about the submission encryption.
Well, not difficult, right?
And now we go to the part two about the RSA algorithm.
So RSA algorithm was invented by these three guys, Rivest, Shamir, and Edelman, so developed
in 1977.
So this RSA algorithm is the most widely used general purpose approach to the public key
encryption.
So in this algorithm, we will assume that the cipher, so this is the cipher in which
the plaintext and the ciphertext are integers between 0 and M-1 for some n.
A table size for n is 1024 bits or 309 decimal digits.
So we'll assume that while you encrypt your original message, M should be, well, the M,
the length is the same as the, well, almost to be this same size as n.
So n is 1024 bits.
So n, the size also is, yeah, should be almost 1024 bits.
This is the plaintext.
The plaintext should be smaller than your chosen n.
We look at how we can get the RSA algorithm from our studied Euler's theorem.
So Euler's theorem tells you that for every n and n, that are relative prime.
So relative prime is the gcd, n, n is 1, the relative prime.
Then we have this function, a to the phi n is congruent to 1 mod n.
So phi means the number of data that are relative prime to n.
The total number of those data to be relative prime to n.
And those data should be in the range from 1 to a mass 1.
Well, if both sides with times a, we have the a to the phi n plus 1 is congruent to
a mod n.
Of course, we know a general form is, from this one we have a phi n to the k's.
This is congruent to 1 to the k.
This is congruent to 1 mod n, right?
Well, for this one, so this one actually equals a to the k times phi n is congruent to 1 mod
n.
Both sides with times a, we have a to the k times phi n plus 1 is congruent to a mod
So from a to a, that means a is the plaintext.
So that means somehow from a, we can get a subtext c.
From c, after some operation, we get back to the original plaintext a again.
In the RSA algorithm, we assume that, how about we use some t as the public key and
private key to do the encryption-decryption.
So suppose a, we apply the public key, then we get it's congruent to the subtext c when
it takes mod n operation.
This is fine, right?
a with some exponential operation, mod n we get a subtext c.
So c, after some exponential operation, c to the d, we require to get the original plaintext
a mod n.
The left-hand side is encryption, the right-hand side is decryption.
Okay, we substitute this ae to c.
So that means we have a to the e to the d is congruent to a mod n.
Then we have a to the e to the d is congruent to a mod n.
Okay, if we compare these two, right?
So these two implies, how about we let e times d equals k times phi n plus 1.
Then we can attain this purpose.
So we find one e such that ed equals k times phi n plus 1.
Then we use a to the e mod n, we get a subtext c.
So using d, c to the d mod n, we get back to the original message a again, right?
Okay, ed equals k times phi n, k can be an integer.
In this mod operation, in fact, in this mod operation, that means e times d is congruent to 1.
We have mod phi n operation.
And this d is called module inverse of e mod phi n, right?
e times d is congruent to 1, so d is a module inverse,
a multiplicative module inverse of e mod phi n.
So last time we studied the module inverse, we studied the Euler's theorem, right?
And we study how to calculate the phi n given an n, given an integer n.
In the RSA algorithm, normally we will choose n to be the product of two very large prime numbers, p and q.
So n will be a product of two primes.
So n equals p times q, this implies the phi n equals p must 1 times q must 1.
So you can choose very large two prime number p and q, then you will get the phi n.
So the next step you can choose an e.
So this e should be a prime number.
For example, t is 61.
Anyway, in our test, normally we choose the e to be a prime number, just like 17.
So because it is a prime number, we'll make sure the GCD e and phi n is 1.
If these two are relative prime to each other, their GCD value is 1, then we can get the module inverse.
We get this d is module inverse of e mod phi n.
So we get the private key kd here.
So this is the process in the RSA algorithm, how you can get the public key, the private key.
So you will generate your public key and private key.
The first step is you choose two very large prime numbers, p and q.
You know those p and q, then you can calculate the phi n value, phi equals p must 1 times q must 1.
Then you can choose the public key e.
e is a public key.
And then because this e normally will be a prime number, of course you will guarantee e and phi n will be relative prime.
So you will be able to calculate the module inverse of e mod phi n.
How to calculate this one?
You can use the extended Euclidean algorithm.
So we taught last time how we can use the extended Euclidean algorithm based on the phi n and e to derive the multiplicative inverse of e.
So this module inverse of e mod phi n, that's d.
So d is a private key.
So once you select this e and d, you will guarantee that, well, a to the e, a to the e, you will get the subtext.
So this is called encryption.
Everyone can know your public key e, so everyone else can use your public key to do that encryption and get the subtext c.
This c will be sent to you because only you have the private key.
You can use a private key to do the decryption.
Only you have the d value.
So that means anyone else cannot do the decryption except you.
So from the subtext d or from subtext c, you can apply your private key d and then you will get the original message a from the sender.
You are the receiver.
So this RSA algorithm, well, you can see some properties about this one.
So RSA makes use of an expression with its polynomials.
From m, here is the original message m, m to the e mod n, we get the subtext c.
From subtext c to the d mod n, we get back the original message m.
In this algorithm, the plaintext is encrypted in blocks.
And each block having a binary value less than some number n.
Suppose we will choose the n to be very large to be 124 bits, right?
So you will guarantee that each block with a size should be equal or smaller than 124 bits.
An encryption and decryption of the following form for some plaintext block m.
So m is smaller than n.
So this e and d will guarantee that e times d equals k times phi n plus 1.
We choose e, d to satisfy this requirement.
Because we guarantee that this m, e, d, then this m, e, d equals m to the k times phi n plus 1.
We take the mod n operation.
m with some e operation, then with d operation, then we get back its original message m.
So while this one is correct, you can refer to the previous slide.
Now this one, this equation is correct because we have the orders theorem.
That you can see here, a to the k times phi n plus 1 is coming to a mod n.
So this one is correct. We can derive it from the orders theorem.
Well, in the RSA algorithm, the e n will be the public key.
The private key actually is the d, the small letter d.
So you can see, suppose Alice is a receiver.
So Alice first will generate the pair of keys.
The generation process is here.
First, Alice will select the two very large prime numbers, p and q.
They're not equal to the calculation of n product.
Then we have the phi n value.
So Alice will choose the integer e, make sure gcd phi n e will be 1.
And in this way, we can generate the module inverse of e, mod phi n.
So public key is e n, private key is d and n.
In the encryption, so encryption by Bob.
Bob is the sender.
Bob will use Alice's public key to do the encryption.
So subtext c equals m to the e mod n.
And then Alice is the receiver.
Alice will use her private key to do the decryption.
So only Alice knows the private key d.
So she will apply c to the d mod n to get back the original plaintext message m sent from Bob.
Here is one example.
Suppose the plaintext is 88.
In this example, we assume we have the public key to be 7.
And this is n value and this is e public key to be 7.
And private key d will be 23.
In the encryption, you can see original message m, this is m to the e mod n equals subtext c.
c is 11 will be sent in the channel, in the internet.
And receiver will obtain this subtext c.
Receiver will use his private key d, c to the d mod n to get back original message m to be 88.
So this is RSA algorithm. Is that clear?
Any question, difficulty here?
Well, it seems to be okay to you.
So then let's try to solve this question.
The question asks you to use the extended Euclidean algorithm to calculate the private key from the public key in the previous slide.
So in previous slide we have
the public key to be 7 and 87.
So this is e, this is m, the private key is d.
So d equals 23.
You can use the extended Euclidean algorithm to get the private key d.
How can you get it?
You can follow this slide.
d is the module inverse of e.
So to get the module inverse, you should use the extended Euclidean algorithm.
Okay, can I try?
I give you five minutes to try it.
Some of you have finished the process.
So let's see how we can derive the private key.
To get the private key, first we need to get from n to phi n.
So this n equals 187.
You should factor this number to be two primes, the product.
And this one actually equals 11 times 17.
This implies the phi n equals 10 times 16.
And this is 160.
Okay, fine.
Then you have the e and gcd.
You will guarantee that e and phi n to be one.
To get the gcd value, you can follow the Euclidean algorithm.
In the traceback, you will get the extended Euclidean algorithm.
Then you will get the private key d.
So this process is from 160 equals 7 times 22 plus 6.
So then 7 equals 6 plus 1.
And this one is the gcd value.
When we trace back, 1 equals 7 minus 6.
And this 6 can be represented as...
7 minus 6. 6 can be represented as 160 minus 7 times 22.
So this is 23 times 7 minus 160.
Okay, well, this is one.
Of course, you can see this is phi n.
And this is a private key e.
And this one is d.
So we have the private key d to be 23 in this example.
Okay, now we look at the general form.
Suppose we have a sentence from the center side.
Like, how are you?
And each character, we can decode a character.
h to be some data, 33.
o to be 1, 4.
w to be 22.
space to be 62, so on and so forth, right?
So one sentence can be represented by some data.
And well, in this encoding-decoding,
each block will contain 3, should contain 4 digits.
So every block.
We assume that block 1 contains 33, 1, 4, 4 digits.
And block 2 contains 22, 62, right, 4 digits.
Well, after this encoding, from character to some data,
then we do transmission.
So in the transmission, the receiver and sender,
suppose this sender, sender will first obtain the receiver's
the public key.
So this is the receiver.
Receiver set will first generate the public key.
Receiver will generate the public key and the private key.
Suppose receiver will use the 2 prime numbers to be p, 73,
and q to be 151, and e to be 11.
Then this is the n value, and this one is phi n.
According to the module inverse calculation,
and this one is value d.
e equals module inverse of e mod phi n.
So receiver will generate the private key d to be 5891.
And public key is e and n.
This is a public key.
And public key can be obtained by the sender.
And sender will apply the public key for each block.
First of all, p1, 3314 to the e mod n.
That's a c1, self-text c1.
So first we have c2, c3.
So this c1, c2 will be obtained by receiver.
And c1, for c1, the receiver can apply his private key d
to do the decryption.
So c1 to the d value mod n.
Then the receiver can get p1, 3314.
And 3314 represents h0.
So this is an encryption and decryption process
for a sequence of characters for a long sentence.
Divide sentence into blocks to make sure every block
is smaller than the given value n.
So before transmission, the receiver should generate
its public key and private key.
The public key will be long by sender.
Sender can use receiver's public key to do the encryption.
Receiver can use his private key to do the decryption.
Let's look at another example.
So assume that, well, in this case,
we have p, q to be 7 and 17, respectively.
So n equals p times q.
And phi equals p1, p must 1 times q must 1.
And assume that we choose the e to be 5.
And assume that we want to encrypt the message m equals 8.
So the first step is we should generate the private key d
and then use the private key d.
We can get the subtext c equals m to the e mod n.
So the second step is to calculate the subtext c.
From c, we can derive the m equals c to the d mod n.
So let's have a break of 10 minutes.
So in this break, you can do this practice.
Try to get the d and the c, the subtext.
So let's have a break of 10 minutes.
Thank you.