Okay, anyone got the result?
64, that's correct.
So let's see how we can get the result to be 64.
Okay, we can go back to the previous slide.
Okay, at this part, right?
So we start from this row, one can be represented as 13.
So 13 minus 3 times 4.
And this 3, 13 minus 3 is minus 4 times 6.
3 is from combination of 16 and 13.
16 minus 13.
So this 5 times 13 minus 4 times 16.
Okay, and this 13 can be represented as some combination of 5 times 13.
93 minus 5 times 16.
Minus 4 times 16.
So this 5 times 93, 1.
This 25 minus 4, this is 29 times 16.
All right?
Okay, we want to get mod to the inverse of 16.
Mod 93.
So both sides we take mod 93.
So this part is 0.
And this part, that means this is a minus 29 is a multi-inverse of 16.
So this is component 2, 93 minus 29.
So this equals 64.
Mod 93.
So this is x value, right?
So 64 is the modular inverse of 16 mod 93.
Okay?
Any questions, comments?
So this result is 64.
Okay, now we go to part 3.
So part 3, we'll study the prime numbers.
From prime numbers, we will learn the Feynman theorem.
And then we'll continue with the Euler's theorem.
No problem.
Prime numbers are those numbers with dividers of 1 and itself.
Just like 2, 3, 5, 7, and 11.
All the numbers are called to be composite numbers.
That's 4 and 6.
And we have the fundamental theorem of arithmetic.
That means any integer to be bigger than 1 can be substituted in a unique way as
a equals p1 to the a1 times p2 to the a2 times pk to the at.
So p1 is more than p2.
It's more than pt.
Those are the prime numbers.
And where each ai is positive integer, so a1, a2 are as the exponent part.
For example, 24 can be substituted as 2 to the 3 times 3 to the 1, right?
2 prime numbers to the exponent to be 3 and 1.
OK, here we have all the primes under 2 solid prime numbers.
It's hard to tell which one is a prime number or not.
It's better when the number is very large.
How to test a number is prime?
That's a challenge problem.
Now we look at the Fermat's theorem.
Fermat's theorem states that if p is prime and a is a positive integer, not divisible by p,
then we have a to the p-mass one is congruent to 1 mod p.
So a is a positive integer, not divisible by p.
Suppose p is a prime.
One example just like if p is a prime number 7, so a equals 4 or 10,
So p is not a factor of a, so a is not divisible by p.
Just like in this example, a equals 4, a equals 10.
So p is not a factor of a.
Then we have this equation, a to the p-mass one.
If p-mass one is, in this example, is 6.
So a is 4 to the 6 is congruent to 1 mod 7.
Or 10 to the 6 is congruent to 1 mod 7.
So this is a statement.
And the platform is, well, at both sides with times a,
So the net size is a to the p is congruent to a mod p.
That's mod p.
So this is the Fermat's theorem.
Here is the table to show that for any given, the p to be 19, to be a prime number.
For any number a, a is from, in this column, 1, 2, 3, 0, 18.
For the number a is smaller than p, of course, p is not a factor of a.
So if a is smaller than p, a is not divisible by p, according to the Fermat's theorem.
Or the a to the p-mass one is congruent to 1 mod p.
So if we look at the last column, so here is a to the 18 is congruent to 1 when mod 19.
So the last column, no matter what the value of a, y, or h, the last column for the value to be 1.
Okay, so this is the Fermat's theorem.
To tell you, this is the rule of this problem you can find.
So we need to understand how we can prove this process.
We apply proof for us to understand the modular operation.
In this statement, in Fermat's theorem, if p is prime and a is a positive integer not divisible by p, so we have this equation, y is congruent.
The proof process is quite interesting, so I would like to share it with you.
Suppose we have a set to prove it, we can construct some sets.
So set a with all members 1, 2, 3, till p-mass 1.
So p is a prime number, right?
So in set a, we have p-mass 1, numbers.
Okay, we look at another set.
So another set b.
So b is set, because we have the parameter a here, we want to integrate a in a set of members.
So every member with times a, a, 2a, 3a, and p-mass 1a.
Also we have, so a, all members times a, respectively, we get b, p-mass 1, numbers.
We have mod p operation.
So from b to c, each member will take the mod p operation.
We get a set c, like a mod p, 2a mod p, 3a mod p.
So the last one is p-mass 1 times a mod p.
Okay, now we look at this set c, a mod p, 2a mod p, mod property.
So property is, we have one conclusion to say that any from this set c, any two numbers.
are different.
Any two numbers in this set c are different.
If not, so we run p2 numbers, suppose they are t times a mod p, and s times a mod p.
And we assume that t is bigger than 0, smaller than s, smaller than p-mass 1.
But any two numbers in this set c, any two, so t, s, should be different.
Maybe if there are two numbers, there should be one smaller than p.
The last one is p-mass 1.
No problem, right? We take two numbers.
So if they are the same, they are equal.
And this implies t times a mod p equals s times a mod p.
So this implies t times a is equal to s times a mod p.
We previously learned that if the gcd a, p is 1, so of course because p is a prime number,
and a is not divisible by p.
So in fact, this one implies gcd value a and p is 1.
a is not divisible by p, p is not a prime number of a and p is a prime.
They do not have any common divisor except 1.
But because a does not contain such a p,
p has two functions, one is 1, one is p.
No p, their common divisor is 1.
So we have previously learned that if gcd a, p is 1, this a can be cancelled, can be removed.
So this implies t is common to s mod p.
However, this is not possible.
This contradicts our assumption that two numbers,
p times a and s times a from that group, from cc,
their value should be range from 0 to te.
So from here we show that two distinct numbers have equal value to this.
That's not possible.
So this is a contradiction.
Based on this result, any two numbers are different.
If not the same, any two to be the same, we can have this contradiction.
So now we say any two numbers are different,
and their value,
so we have the cc, we also have p must 1 numbers
in the whole data,
in the range
from 1 to p must 1.
So 0, right?
Because all the numbers, p must 1 to a,
the relative prime of p cannot be 0.
No factor of p.
And you see the difference.
So their range is actually from 1 to p must 1.
When p must 1 numbers, they are all distinct.
No repetition.
p must 1 numbers, that means their value must be from 1 to p must 1.
So this implies actually the set A equals set C.
So this implies set A equals set C.
If set A equals set C, we time all members.
Together, with time A,
this result equals with time all the numbers in set C.
In with time A, we have 1 times 2 times 3 times p must 1.
And the set C, actually it is A times 2A times 3A times p must 1A,
with not p operation.
Right?
Because in set C, we have no p operation.
So the right-hand side, we have how many A?
1 times 2 times 3 times p must 1.
And number of A is A to the power p must 1.
And p must 1 numbers.
Number of A in this fraction will be A to the p must 1.
Minus, this is the more p operation.
And similarly, we have the GCD, 1 times 2 times 3 times p must 1,
with p, this is 1.
1 to the whole relative prime to p.
When coming together, that data is also relative prime to p.
The log is common divided by 1.
So both sides, this factor can be cancelled.
So the left-hand side is 1.
The left-hand side is A to the p must 1.
Number of p is countering 2.
Countering 2, countering 2.
So thus, we have this famous theorem result.
Not very difficult, right?
So in this proof policy, you can see we need to understand
the final number p, and we construct a set with four numbers from 1 to p must 1.
Hopefully, we have p must 1 numbers distinct, different.
And we evolve the factor of A, and we take the both p operations.
Come together, start saying A and C are the same.
So finally, we have this A to the p must 1.
It's common to want more p. We have this result.
So this is a proof policy to understand the mode of operation prime numbers.
Of course, you can test the famous theorem with the A equals 7, p equals 19.
So according to the famous theorem, it is A to p must 1 is common to 1 mod p.
In this example, A is 7, p must 1 is 18,
common to 1 mod 19. Of course, you can refer to previous table, right?
The 7 on this row is 1. Of course, it is 1.
We look at another important concept. It's called the Euler's total function phi n.
So phi is used in the RSA algorithm.
So phi n is the number of positive integers raised by n and raised from prime to n.
So we define if n equals 1, we have 1.
If n equals 2, the number of positive integers raised by n is 2.
And then raised from prime to n, we have a single one, 1.
Because GCD to 1 is 1.
These are 3. We have two numbers.
2 and 1, smaller than 3, and raised from prime to 3, we have two numbers, 2.
And 4, one of those two numbers, 1 and 3, right?
Two numbers. This one, 4 and raised from prime to 4, 1 is 3.
5, we have 1, 2, 3, 4, right?
We have 4 numbers, 4. 6, we have 1 and 5, two numbers.
7, we have 1 to 6. 8, we have 1, 3, 5, 7.
And 9, we have 1, 2, 4, 5, 7, 8, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, here.
So 10, we have 1, 3, 7, 9, right?
4 numbers.
And on the top board, you can find this phi n to denote all the numbers.
This is the given n and the relative prime to n, representing how many of those numbers.
Okay, based on this, all those totient function phi n, if p is a prime number, of course, all the numbers from 1, 2, 3, till p must 1, all of them are relative prime.
So they are relative, relative prime.
Come to p.
So this phi p is p must 1. The comedy value is 1.
So very cheap.
Okay, if n equals p to the k, and p is prime, then phi n equals p, k, then minus p, k must not mean.
If p is prime, then phi n equals p, k, then minus p, k must not mean.
So one example, suppose, we'll just like...
One example is, if n is 8, p is 2, 8 equals 2 to the 3, right?
So phi n equals phi 8 equals 2 to the 3 minus 2 to the 2.
This is 8 minus 4, which is 4.
So phi 8 equals 4. According to this equation, it shows the result is true.
So of course, what we can see is, we should remove all the elements that are not relative prime to p.
That means we should remove all members who contains a factor of p.
So in this example also, we can construct two sets. Set A with all members from 1, 2, 3, till p, k must 1.
So this is set with all members to be smaller than n, so we have p, k must 1 numbers.
In set B, we should remove all members that contains a factor of p.
Smallest one is p, right?
We have 2p, 3p.
So the last one is p times...
So the last one actually is p, k minus p.
So this one can be represented as p times p k must 1 must 1.
Right?
Okay, so this phi n equals the number of elements in A must number of elements in B, because all members in B contains the common divider of p.
Just like n, n contains the p.
And 1, no other numbers.
So we should remove all the numbers with p as a factor.
For the number of elements in p, it is from 1, 2, 3, till p, k must 1 must 1.
So this number of p of B, number of A is here.
p, k must 1.
Number of B is here.
p, k must 1 must 1.
And also we have the result.
p, k must p, k must 2.
And we have this result.
Another very important property is if n equals p times q, well both p and q are prime numbers, the phi n equals p must 1 times q must 1.
So this one, I put it in an exercise for your homomorph.
You can take home and exercise, think about how you can prove this property.
Well 31 is a prime number, right?
So 31 is a prime number p, and this equals p must 1, so this equals 30.
And 32, this is 2 to the 5, so this equals 2 to the 5 must 2 to the 4 is 16.
33 is 3 times 11, 2 prime numbers, the product.
So this equals 2 times 10 is 20.
34, it is 2 times 17, 2 prime numbers.
This equals 1 times 16.
So this is 5 times 7, this is 4 times 6, this is 4.
Okay, you can well do it by yourself to check whether you can try this property of previous one to get the result.
So this is the definition and some calculation of the Euler's theorem.
From Euler's common function, we have this Euler's theorem.
The Euler's theorem states that for every a and n, there are relative primes.
Relative prime.
Relative prime means n is not an or relative prime.
So that means gct an equals 1.
So this is only the product.
Then we have a to the 5n is compared to 1 mod n.
So one example suppose a equals 4, n equals 15, so gct a, gct 4, and 15, the greatest common divisor is 1.
We should first calculate the 5, 15.
15 equals 3 times 5, 2 prime numbers.
So this 2 times 4 equals 8.
According to this Euler's theorem, we have 4 to the 8 is compared to 1 mod 15.
So this is 5n, this is a, this is n.
If we times a at both sides, this times a, this times a, we have a to the 5n plus 1 is compared to a mod n.
So this one, in fact, you can see is very close to our some encryption process.
You can regard a to be a message after some operation.
You take it and you can get a back.
So this is a, you do some encryption and you do some decryption, somehow you get the result to be same.
So we are very close to the public key scheme, the original RSA algorithm.
Okay, for this one, we also can prove it.
And the proof process is quite close to the Fermat's algorithm.
We can construct 3 sets A set with all members, T1, T2, T3, 5n.
So these are all the data that are very close to n.
Because n is not a prime number anymore, we only select those numbers that are very close to n.
And total number is 5, this definition of 5n.
So we have 5n numbers.
So remember 5n is all the numbers that are less than n and are relative to prime to n.
Within this total number, 5n.
Okay, similarly, we can construct B to times A.
So we have this set T1 times A, T2 times A, and here T5n times A.
Similarly, we have 5 numbers, and then we take the mod n operation, then we get a safe C.
So we have T1 times A, mod n, T2 times A, mod n, T5n times A, mod n.
And similarly, we can argue any two from this set C. Any two are different.
The reason is because GCD A n is 1, GCD NTI n is also T1.
NTI from set A, their GCD value is 1, and GCD A n is 1.
So we have this result, cannot be the same. Otherwise, we have the same condition as in the theorem.
If any two are different, that means in this set, we also have 5n numbers.
So this is because we have this even condition.
So that means from the set C, we have 5n distinct numbers.
And this T1 times A, T5 times A, mod n value.
That result is also 20.2n.
So also you can have this conclusion, the GCD NTI times A, mod n, that value with n is also to be 1.
So T1 times A has no common divisor with n.
T1 times A has no common divisor with n.
So T1 times A also has no common divisor with n.
So those two are virtually prime.
Based on this fact, we all give all the methods in set C are different and are virtually prime to n.
So let me tell you we have 5n numbers.
So this implies A equals C.
So pi A equals pi C. So pi means the product of all members in the set.
We take the mod n operation.
And this finally we have with time A together, we have T1 times T2 times T5n equals the right hand side we have T1 times A, mod n.
This one times T2 times A, mod n, so on and so forth.
And the right hand side is T1 times T2 times T5n.
And for A, we only have 5n times.
So we have 5n numbers. And this part can be cancelled.
So this implies mod n operation.
So this implies the A times n is equal to 1 when mod n is the operation.
Okay, you can regard this one with the whole process why the honest theorem is correct.
So now we can test the honest theorem with these small numbers.
The first one, n is 10. First we need to calculate 5n.
So this n equals 2 times 5, 2 prime numbers. So 5 equals 1 times 4 is 4.
According to the honest theorem, it is A to the 5n, 5 is 4, 1 to 1, mod n.
So A is 3, 3 to the 4, it is 81.
So it is equal to 1 when mod 10.
This is true. We look at the second one.
And this 2 to the 10 mod 11, we know it is 124.
So 124 equals 93 times 11 plus 1.
So this one is 1 to 1.
Okay, well for this honest theorem, actually you can see it is very close to the public key scheme.
A is a vintage, often some operations. We can get back to A itself.
So this is the public key scheme, very close.
So we skip our break. So let's try to finish our part 4.
Part 4 talks about how we can apply very efficient model operations for very large numbers.
And then we can apply the CRT, the Chinese Remainder Theorem. So what are the purposes for this one?
The Chinese Remainder Theorem tells you that
Given we have a very large number of exponential operations mod some prime numbers,
we can have this quick way to decide the result.
The reason is because in the RSA algorithm, we need to calculate the message to public key mod a given number n.
And this n can be factor to be two prime numbers in the key.
In RSA algorithm, we will show two big prime numbers in the key.
So e is a given public key. So normally we need to do this kind of calculation.
However, because n is very large, we can first calculate m e, m to the e is also very large.
But once we have this m e mod p, we get some R1 value.
So these two values will be much easier to calculate compared to any mod n because both p and t are much smaller.
So the Chinese Remainder Theorem tells you that from these two equations, we get a unique number x, a unique x.
To be smaller than n, we can decide the result.
So CRT, this theorem can tell you that we can calculate this thing.
And this thing in fact equals the original big number m to the e mod n.
Rather than to calculate m e mod s to the e, we can calculate m e mod t and m e mod 2.
From two Remainders, we will calculate the CRT algorithm. We can quickly get x like here.
So that's the purpose we will calculate the CRT from this operation here.
To make your calculation to be four times faster than the original calculation.
Okay, so this is the purpose.
Now we look at what's the meaning for Chinese Remainder Theorem.
And this one is believed to have been discovered by the Chinese mathematician Shen Tzu.
In a round 100 AD, and this one is one of the most useful results of number theory,
it says that it is possible to reconstruct integers in a certain range from their residue modular or set of pairwise vector prime modular lines.
Okay, you know the story, right?
So now you don't know the number, but you count a group of items, 3 by 3, then the net is 2.
You count all the numbers 5 by 5, because you divide the numbers by 5, the remainder is 3.
You count them by 7, the net remainder will be 2.
The question is, what's the original number of items here?
So you can find this story in the She Diao Yin Cong Zhuo, used by Jin Yong to test how smart you are.
Okay, we can have a formal definition of this theory.
Then n1, n sub 1, n sub 2 sub k, the integers written on 1, we call them to be modular or divisors.
And this is denoted by n, the product of the ni.
So n is n1, n sub 1 times n sub 2 times n sub k.
The Chinese remainder theorem asserts that if the ni or pairwise co-prime,
so pairwise co-prime, that means just like GCD, ni, nj is 1.
And n2, the greatest common divider is 1.
And if n1, n sub 1, n sub k are integers, but that will kill the ai in this range for every i, then there is only one integer x.
So we have this x in this range, and the remainder of the Euclidean division of x by ni is ai for every i.
In other words, this x, well, mod ni, we have a1, and the mod nk, we have ak.
So from all these k equations, we say we have a unique x.
So this x is smaller than n, non-negative.
Next, divided by n sub 1, the remainder is a1.
Finally, we have this k equations.
The Chinese remainder theorem tells you that we have a unique x in this range, 1x, to stand by all k equations.
So one example here is suppose x, according to previous problem, we count x by 3, the left is 2.
We count all x by 5, the left is 3, we count x by 7, so divide it by 7, 7 by 7, 7 as a group.
The remainder is 2, what's the original x?
So we have 3 propositions, p1, p2, p3.
From proposition 1, of course, from this one, we have, easily we can get x equals 3 times t plus 2.
3 times 3 times 2.
So from proposition 1, we have this one.
From this, well, if x equals this value, we use the second proposition.
So second proposition means 3t plus 2, when we mod 5, so we mod 5, this is congruent to 3.
So from proposition 2, this means, well, x mod 5 equals 3.
So this implies before 2, both sides, we have minus 2.
So 3t is congruent to 3 minus 2, mod 5.
So we have this one equation, 3t is congruent to 1, mod 5.
This is the result of the second proposition.
So what is the mod 5 operation? If t, we look at t.
So t value can be anyone from 0, 1, 2, 3, 4.
Because it is mod 5, we don't need to use t to define mod 5 because we have a loop.
If t is 0, mod 5 is 0. 3t is 0. 3t mod 5 is 0, right?
If t is 1, 3t is, what's the value?
What's the value? 3. 3t mod 5 is 3.
If t is 2, 3t is 1. 6. 3t mod 5 is 1.
t is 3, 3t is 9, mod 5, 4. 4, 3t, 12.
2, right? If t is 5, beyond 0.
Okay, we have the result 3t mod 5 is 1.
That means this row. So this implies t mod 5 should be 2.
t mod 5 should be 2. t mod 5 can be 1 times 0 times 1 times 2 times 3 times 4.
So only if t is 2, then 3t will be 1.
So we have this equation 4. t can be represented as 1.
So t can be represented as 5s plus 2.
Mod 5 equals 2. 5s equals 2.
So that means from both P1 and P2, we have this x.
We have x equals 3t plus 2.
And this t, 5s plus 2, to substitute this t, we have 3 times 5s plus 2 plus 2.
So we have 15s plus 8.
From proposition P1 and proposition 2, we have the conclusion
x can be represented as 15s plus 8.
Is that clear?
If we only have two propositions, so we can say the original x can be 8.
If we only have one proposition, we can say we count the items.
If only this condition, the original number of items can be what? 2, right?
Just two items. We count them by 3, we leave it 2. So 2 is the correct answer.
So now suppose we have two propositions. We count them 5 by 5.
So that is 3. Then we have the answer.
The original items can be 8.
So A satisfied proposition 1 in order of proposition 2.
But we have three conditions, three constraints. So we need to continue.
Now we look at proposition 3.
So because x is 15s plus 1, we take mod 7 operation.
Mod 7, so this is actually can be represented as 14s plus 7 plus 1.
We convert to mod 7.
So 14s mod 7 is 0. This is 0.
And we have s plus 1, s plus 1, convert to 2, mod 7.
So this one implies s mod 7 equals 1.
S mod 7 equals 1. So s plus 1 mod 7 equals 2.
For us, we mod 1, we get this equation.
So s mod 7 equals 1.
Then we have s can be represented as 7 times u plus 1.
So this s, we can substitute s to be here.
Then finally we have x to be 105 times u plus 23.
So s equals 7u plus 1.
We look at x, that equation.
Substitute s by 7u plus 1, so we have x equals 105 times u plus 23.
And this is the general form to represent the value of x.
And note that 105 is a deep common model of 357.
357 or the modular here. 357.
So then we have a solution 23, 128, 233.
Model of 105.
However, in this range, 3 times 5.
3 times 5 times 7, this equals 5.
We have a unique x to be 23.
So of course, the original number according to that counting is not unique.
We have 23, 128.
But to be smaller than that, 105, we have a unique value to be 23.
This is the problem.
Okay, now we have this exercise.
Suppose x plus 5 is 3.
x plus 7 is 4.
What's x?
I give you 5 minutes.
Anyone can provide the correct answer.
Then you can eat. Otherwise, they eat.
So tell me.
What's x? Tell me.
What's x?
.