Okay, let's continue.
So I'm glad some of you come here and ask me some questions, and some questions are
really good.
Okay.
Well, I will review some answers later, just like why this RSA acronym is difficult for
some attacker to know the private key.
And also some still ask me, can we apply the CRT, the Chinese remanded that theorem in
this calculation?
Of course, we can apply it here.
Well, let's look at this exercise.
What's the D value?
Can you tell me what's the D value?
Anyone got the answer?
D is 77.
Okay, that's right.
So let's have a quick calculation here.
The phi n equals p must 1 times q must 1.
This is 6 times 16, that's 96.
Okay, well, we have e equals 5.
And we should guarantee that GCD e phi n is 1.
This is the process to get the, we apply the Euclidean algorithm.
And this is 96 equals 5 times 19 plus 1, very easy, right?
1 is the GCD value.
So 1 equals 96 minus 5 times 19, 96 is phi n, and 5 is e.
So that means D is congruent to minus 19, is congruent to phi n, phi n is 96.
So 96 minus 19, this is 77 mod phi n, okay?
We should have the party integer as the private key.
Next slide, we should get the C value.
So anyone of you get the C value?
What's C?
C value is m to the e mod n, and m is small, is 8, e is 5, n is 1, 1, 9, right?
So n equals p times q, 1, 1, 9.
So this value is 43, okay?
Quite easy to get.
The next step is we should get the original message m from C. So m equals C to the D
mod n, so C is 43, D is 77, mod 1, 1, 9.
Okay, here the data is quite large.
So now we can apply the CRT theorem.
We studied the part four in lecture two, so we see, well, the CRT can really reduce the
computation time for us to quickly get the result.
This one, suppose the value is x, x equals 43 to the 77 mod 1, 1, 9.
So we know n equals p times q equals 7 times 17.
So when we apply the CRT algorithm, that means we should first get 43 to the 77 mod 7, we
get x1, 43 to the 77 mod 17, we get x2.
From this x, y, x2, we will be able to get x.
We have a unique x, a unique one.
This one is smaller than 1, 1, 9, smaller than n value.
So this is the conclusion from the CRT theorem, right?
So instead of mod 1, 1, 9, so 1, 1, 9 is very large, because 1, 1, 9 equals 7 times 17, a part of 2 prime number.
So we can calculate that big number, mod 7, we get x1, mod 17, we get x2.
From these two equations, we are able to get a unique x.
This x is smaller than 1, 1, 9, a unique one.
So this x equals this x, that's n.
This y, last time we introduced CRT.
So here is actually we can quickly get x1.
What we have is 7 is a prime number, right?
So this one, first we look at 43 to the 77, this equals 43 equals 7 times 6 plus 1 to the 77, mod 7, right?
Mod 7, this part is 0.
OK, 1, mod 7, this equals 1.
So this is x1, very fast, right?
OK, we look at second part, 43 to the 77 in terms of 17, so 17 times 2 plus 9.
And in the exponent part, we can apply the Fermat's theorem.
Fermat's theorem, that means we mod p, in the exponent part, we should get the p-mass-1.
So p-mass-1, that's 16 times 4 plus 17, well, mod 17.
So in the Fermat's theorem, we have a to the p-mass-1 is congruent to 1 mod p, OK?
This is relationship p, here we have p-mass-1.
So that's the reason we have 16 here.
So this part is 0, and this part 16 actually is congruent to 1, also can be removed.
And well, so this one is congruent to 9 to the 13, mod 17.
And this number is not very large, so we directly get the result to be 8.
This is x2, very quick.
So now from the x1, x2, we will get the unique x in the range from 0 to 1, 1, 9.
So that means x mod 7 equals 1, x mod 17 equals 8, right?
By applying the CRT, so we can get x equals 17 t plus 8.
We substitute x to be in the first equation, so this we have 2 times 7 plus 3 t plus 7
plus 1 is congruent to 1 mod 7.
So times 7 is 0, times 7 is 0, so this implies 3 t plus 1 congruent to 1 mod 7.
So you can see this one can be cancelled, this implies t is congruent to 0 mod 7.
We can simply let t to be 0.
If t is 0, then x is 8.
So t is 0, that means t can take 0, then x is 8.
So we get the original message m to be 8.
Is that clear?
So we apply the CRT theorem here, and you should be able to apply CRT, this theorem
in your calculation.
It could be required in your midterm test.
So of course I will try to design the number to be not that large, just like in this example,
you can well quickly cancel some data and get the result to make the calculator to
be smaller, and then you can use your calculator to quickly get like x, y, x2, any questions?
Okay, so now we move to our part 3.
Part 3 is about Diffie-Hellman algorithm, and this one is also very important.
So in mining cryptography, we talk about RSA, we talk about the Diffie-Hellman.
This algorithm is principle, very important.
So in the Diffie-Hellman algorithm, we should have two very large numbers.
So y is p, and so y is primitive root g, or p.
So primitive root, in some cases, we call it to be generator.
And both p and g are public null, and p should be at least 112 bits, p is very large.
Suppose we have two users, Alice and Bob.
So Alice will choose a private value a, and Bob will choose a private data b.
And locally, each user will do the calculation.
So Alice will do the calculation based on the generator g, g to the a, a is a private
data.
So Alice can calculate g to the a mod p.
So gp or polynomial.
And Bob will locally calculate small y, y equals g to the b mod p.
Then these two values, x, y will be exchanged, so that means x will be sent to Bob, y will
be sent to Alice.
And well, then Alice and Bob will do the following calculation.
So Alice get y from Bob, and she will use y to the a mod p to get the key a.
So this key a, in fact, equals y is g to the b, that's what, value.
So y is g to the b, mod p, g to the b.
And then we have the exponent a here, mod p.
And this equals g to the a times b, mod p.
And similarly, Bob will do this calculation, x to the b mod p.
x is obtained from Alice, x equals g to the a.
So this part is x, this part is small y, mod p.
This one also equals g to the a times b, mod p.
So algebraically, it can be shown that ka equals kb.
So in this way, Alice and Bob now have a symmetric key for communications.
In a symmetric communication, in a symmetric key scheme, both users, like in the AES, they
should have a secret key k.
And Diffie-Hellman algorithm can allow them to calculate this key k for the communication.
So this process, based on Diffie-Hellman algorithm, Alice will locally choose gp to be known,
and this one will only be known by small a.
So Alice will calculate the big a.
These three data will be sent to Bob.
Bob will use his locally chosen data b, a secret to Bob, to calculate gb.
So Bob will get k, the same key k, equals a to the b mod p.
And Alice will calculate this b obtained from Bob.
So Alice will get the same k to be b to the a mod p.
And this key k is the same.
So later, Alice and Bob can do the encryption-decryption using the same key k in their communicated
messages.
Is that clear?
So they only have the g is a primitive root, p is a very large prime number.
We look at this example, suppose Alice and Bob get public numbers p to be 23 and g to
be 9.
So suppose Alice chooses the private data to be 4 and Bob chooses the private data to
be 3.
And they will compute x, y locally.
Alice will calculate x, Bob will calculate y using the public number p and g.
So in this example, x equals 9 to the 4th mod 23.
And this is the value to be 6561 mod 23, this is 6.
And Bob will calculate line to the cube mod 23.
And this is 7 to line mod 23.
This is 16.
And this 6 will be sent to Bob and 16 will be sent to Alice.
So Alice will do the calculation to get the symmetric key.
And previously, we can see Alice will get 16.
16 to the local data to be 4 mod p.
So p is 23.
And this value is 9.
Bob will get x from Alice.
So Bob will get 6.
So this 6 to his local data of 3 mod p again.
And this value is also 9.
So Alice and Bob now have the symmetric key line.
So this key k can be used for encryption and decryption in a symmetric encryption scheme.
Any questions?
Okay if no question, can you use 5 minutes to solve this exercise?
So in this exercise, you should be able to calculate the same key obtained by Alice and Bob.
Okay, some of you have finished, so I can share with you the result here.
In this example, we have the public key here to be p and g.
So p is 23, that's p and g, the generator is 5.
Well Alice chose the secret integer a equals 4, b is 3.
So Alice will calculate x is g to the a mod p, 5 to the 4 mod p is 23.
This x is 4.
So Bob will calculate y, g to the b mod p is g to the 3 mod 23.
This is 10.
Because here we ask you to show the key exchange process, right?
So you should show this intermediate result and this x will be sent to Bob and y will be sent to Alice.
So finally the key k equals x to the a again, sorry, x to the b, this is a calculation just like Bob, x to the b mod p.
In fact, this equals g to the a b mod p.
So x to the b is 10 to the b is 3, mod 23, this is 18.
Similarly, Alice can get the key k equals y from Bob to the a mod p, y is 10, a is 4, mod p is 23, this is also 18.
So this is equals the g a b, g is 5, a times b is 4 times 3, mod p 23, this is 18.
Okay, so we finished this part two about the Diffie-Hellman algorithm, part three.
So any question, comments?
For this lecture time, we stop here. Today we have the lab one and T is here, so we have a break probably five minutes for the sit-up of your lab.
So we finish here, thank you.
Thank you.