Hello. Hello. Hello. Okay. Good evening, everyone. So, this is today's lecture. So, welcome to
thank you for your attendance. Today is the day before the holiday tomorrow. You're still here.
I'm very glad to see you. Okay. Last time, let's have a brief review about what we have learned
last time about the digital signature. So, in digital signature in part one,
we finished part one about the RSA algorithm, how this one can be used to generate the RSA signature.
So, we have the signature generation and the signature verification.
So, because we have the public key and the private key in the RSA algorithm,
and the private key can be used to generate the signature, and the public key can be used by the
receiver to verify the correctness of your signature. So, you can see this process, you can see,
so we use the private key D to generate the signature S, and at the receiver side,
receiver will use the sender's public key to do the verification. So, in this way, we guarantee
the message is really from the sender like from Alice. So, we have this example to show how you can
generate the public key, private key, and how we can generate the signature, and also how can we
apply the Chinese remainder theorem to quickly calculate a large number, but in generation,
in the verification of the signature. So, step three is verification,
whether the signature is correct.
Now, we look at part two, and part two is another signature scheme. We call it to be the
ALKMA digital signature. So, this one is based on the DLP problem. So, DLP problem is a discrete
logarithm problem. So, this one is also believed to be very hard to attack.
So, now, first, we look at the discrete logarithm problem, just like, you know,
abbreviation to be DLP problem. The input for this problem, we have the input. So, input is ZP star.
So, this is a set. This is a set of DLP problems. So, this is a set of DLP problems. So,
this is a set
with all members from 1, 2, 3, till P must 1, and we assume P is a prime number.
So, this set contains all the numbers from 1 to P must 1. And we have another data G in this set.
So, G is a generator of ZP star. So, generator, or in some cases, we say it is a primitive root.
So, generator means
for any i
in this ZP star,
so, G i mod P,
G i mod P,
and these four members
in ZP star.
Okay, this is a good property for G to be a generator of ZP star. So, what's the meaning?
Well, in fact, we can look at this example. So, in this example,
we have table. So, we have the B, the value B, right, can be from 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
So, here P is a prime number to be 7. So, this ZP star
is this set X. So, X can take any value from 1 to 6. And we look at which B, B is the base,
right, B is the base, just like previously the G. So, G i, we look at these two rows.
When B equals 3 and B equals 5. So, you can see G B i. So, in this example, it is B i
mod P,
P is 7. So, we look at BX mod 7, and the result can represent
all members in the set X. So, when we take the B to be the value to be 3, so we can see B1 mod 7
is 3, right, because B equals 3. And B squared, that's 3 times 3 is 9, 9 mod 7, we have 2.
And B cubed, 2 times 3, that's 6. B to the fourth, that's 6 times 3, that's 18,
mod 7, we have 4. So, 4 times 3, that's 12, 12 mod 7, we have 5. 5 times 3, that's 15,
mod 7, we have 1. And all the results you can see, we can have all members 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6,
all the members in the set X, right? And thus, we say B equals 3, these two are the generators.
Generators.
For B equals 3 or 5, so these two data can be the generators in this example. For P
equals 7. However, if B equals 2, and the result will be repeated with only
2, 4, 1, and 2, 4, 1 repeated. So, when B equals 2, we cannot get all members in the set X. So,
set X is ZP star, right? In other words, B cannot be 2 or 4 or 6 to be the generator.
We need to guarantee when I take the value from 1 to 6, the result can list all members in the set
X. Is that clear? Okay, so this is the definition about the generator. So, in some cases,
we call it to be the primitive root. And given that B is a number in the set ZP star,
and this is create logarithm problem, we'll ask you to find a unique number A. So, this A is
smaller than the P, such that G to the A is congruent to B more P. Okay, we want to find
this exponent number A such that G to the A more P equals B. So, we denote this value A as discrete
log of the number B for the base G more P. So, we have this GP the meaning. So, in fact, if we have
for A, if we have A, G and P to calculate B, this is easy, right?
With the value A, G, P to calculate B, it is easy. However, with the G, with G, this generator, P
and B to calculate A, this is very difficult, very difficult.
So, currently, we do not have a convenient way to get A easily. So, this is actually an exponential
problem where probably we need to try all possibilities. So, we have this assumption.
This assumption is called the DL assumption. So, this assumption says there is no efficient
algorithm in polynomial time. So, non-exponential time to solve DL problem. So, this is DL problem,
okay? Given G, P, B to get A, this is the DL problem. Well, today, it is still widely believed
that this assumption holds. It is true, very difficult. So, difficulty is said is similar
to the RSA algorithm. When you have a big N, you will find P times Q, this factorization.
The difficulty of factorization will be similar to this DL problem, similar difficulty.
Given that just like the P can be very large with a size like to be 1 or 24 bits, okay? A very large
number. In that case, it is difficult for you to calculate the A given B.
So, here we have explained this table, right? Just we list the base B, and when B equals 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6,
and B, I, more P, what's the result in this table? And we can see only when B equals 3 or 5,
we can get all possible result to make the result to equal the set ZP star.
So, according to previous table, we look at how can we solve the DLP problem.
As we know, if the base equals B or G equals 3. So, G equals 3, 3 squared plus 7 is 2.
So, for this discrete log of 2, we want to get its exponent. So, exponent number should be 2 here.
So, the discrete log of 2 for the base 3, this is G mod 7, this is P. The exponent in this example
should be 2. Well, for this example, because 3 cubed plus 7, we have 6. And this discrete log of 6,
for the base 3 mod 7, the exponent should be 3. And similarly, this 5, we have the result to be
5. So, how about this one? Well, if the base is 2 and the B is 4, if base is 2
and the result is 4. So, in fact, we can find two cases.
This is case 1. This is case 2. And this shows that the exponent can be either 2 or 5. So, we do not
have a unique result. The result can be either 2 or 5. But, because the B, G to the G squared mod 7,
is 4, and also G to the 5 mod 7, is also 4.
So, the reason is because G equals 2 is not a generator.
The result will not be unique. So, this is not allowed. We must choose the
the base G to be a generator, such that in this discrete log calculation, the result will be unique.
Okay, based on the DLP problem, we look at how we can construct some of the public key and private
key. And now we look at for this DLP problem, some property for this problem. If P is small,
discrete log can be found by exhaustive search. Now, we can try all possible of i.
So, i, we can exhaustive search i in this set,
JP star, right? From 1, 2, 3,
4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 29, 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, 34, 35, 36, 37, 38, 39, 40, 41, 42, 43, 44, 45, 44, 45, 46, 46, 47, 48, 49, 50, 51, 52, 53, 52, 53, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54, 54
trial or possibilities to see which exponent to make the result equals the given p, okay?
Well, we will make the p to be very large. So the size of prime p for which dl can be computed
is approximately the same size, the same as the size of integers that can be
factored. So normally we will choose the p to be one or 24 bits. At this moment,
this size is believed to be quite secure. For the deal problem, this is in fact an example
one-way function. So one function means from g, p, and a to get,
or we say x, to get y. So this
is, this means we can calculate the function g to the x mod p to get y. Finding fx, this is easy.
However, given y, finding x, to certify this equation, it is hard. In the deal problem,
that means given g, p, y to find x, this is very difficult because you need to guarantee
p gx mod p equals y. So this is almost impossible, okay? If the p is very large, to get this x is
almost impossible. So based on this good property, we have the l comma signature scheme.
So you can see different cryptography based on different mathematical problems. The RSA is based
on the factorization of a big number, the difficulty. And this one is based on the difficulty of the deal
problem. This scheme is based on the difficulty of computing discrete logarithm over the zp
over this set. So p is prime. In this signature scheme, we have the setup and the key generation
step. And suppose Alice is the one to use this scheme. Alice will choose large prime p.
Well, so p minus one, p is an odd number. So p minus one is an even number, right? Even number.
So seven, if p equals seven, p minus one is six. Six is an even number. So even number must have
some prime factor. And we will require p minus one has a large prime factor. So p minus one is
has a large prime factor. So this is for the security purpose.
Security purpose.
Then for the given p, we are able to know which data is a primitive root
or primitive element. So this is the meaning of generator.
So we choose one data to be the generator to the prime number p, okay? So given the p is prime,
the multiple number can be the generator. So we choose one. And then Alice will choose
x, small x as her private key and calculate the gx small p to get y. The public key is p, g and y.
The primary key for Alice is this x, right? From x to get y is easy.
And then to sign a message, this is a big x. Alice needs to choose an integer k. So this k,
we can say this k is a one-time random key.
For one message x, we will choose one key, one different key, k. So this key k should be
smaller than or equal to p minus one. And also we need to guarantee that the gcd, k and p minus one
is one, the relative prime, because we need to calculate this module inverse. So this will
guarantee that we have the k minus one mod p minus one. So there are relatively primes
and this means we are able to calculate the module inverse of k mod p minus one.
And then Alice will calculate gk mod p to be r. Well, in this way, r will be the signature.
So rs will be the signature. So you can see the k is a one-time random key, right? But gk mod p
equals r, the r will be no. However, with r, you cannot know the k. So this key k will not be
disclosed. The receiver will only get r and s. Now we look at what's s. So s equals
module inverse of k minus one. Here we mod p minus one. So we have k minus one times,
this is the message x minus the private key of Alice times r. So r from here, and Alice has a
private key, right? So of course Alice is able to calculate the k minus one times the message
minus her private key times r and then mod p minus one to be another signature s.
The send message is the message end with the r and s. r and s will be sent along with x to the
receiver like Bob. When Bob received this message, Bob will do the signature verification.
To verify the message, Bob will do the comparison of g to the x and y to the r times r to the s.
So y is the public key.
So these are the public key, public key now g, p, and y to be known by receiver by Bob.
g, p, y is a public key to be known by anyone else. Okay, we want to know why this equation is
true. The gx equals yr times rs. That means your signature is correct. So of course you can see
the receiver will use Alice, the public key,
in the verification, right? y is the public key of Alice. So this public key will be sent to Bob.
So Bob will use Alice's public key r in the verification. So in this way Bob will guarantee
the message is really from Alice because I'm using your public key y in this verification. So small r,
is really from Alice because I'm using your public key y in this verification.
So small r, small s are the signed signature you sent to me. I use your public key y in the
verification. So g is the public key and also I apply the message in the verification, right?
So no one else can fabricate this data because I'm using that message and I'm using your public key
in this verification. So now we look at why this gx equals y to the r times r to the s.
So g to the x, this is a x is a capital x is a message. So in fact we look at the second equation.
So second equation means at both sides we can time at both sides with times k, right? So we have
k times s, then the right hand side k times k to the mass one, that's one.
It's congruent to one mod p mass one, right? So that means this k mass one can be cancelled.
So that means this k mass one can be cancelled. Then we have x minus x r
is congruent to x mass minus x r mod p mass one. In other words,
this x capital x minus x r, well this is mod p mass one, right? So this can be represented as
k times s plus let's say t times p mass one.
The congruent, that means the difference will be multiple of p mass one.
So both sides we mod p mass one, then we have that equation, right?
The difference will be a multiple of p mass one, multiple we use t to represent this multiple.
Okay, this is congruent, but here we have equation, because we use t to represent the difference.
And this implies the capital X equals k times s plus x r times t times p mass one.
So then the gx, so gx equals g to this part, right? Well, if we mod p,
mod p, according to the Fermat's theorem, we know that g to the t times p mass one is congruent to
one mod p, because p is a prime number. This is a Fermat's theorem. So this part can be removed.
And thus we have g to the x equals ks from here, xr from here.
Is that clear?
Why we have gx equals gxr plus ks? Because start from the second s generation, second equation.
So from this s, so this explains the whole process again. From this s, this equation, right?
Here, at both sides, we times k, that means we move the k mass one to the left hand side.
So we have ks is congruent to x minus xr mod p minus one. The congruent means this x minus x r
can be represented as ks plus t times p minus one, because we have mod p minus one, this operation.
Then this x, the capital X equals k times s plus xr plus t times p minus one.
And thus we have the result here, the gx equals g to the xr plus ks. And this is in the exponent,
we have addition, that can be translated to the multiplication, because this is the exponential
operation. So this equals g to the xr times g to the ks. g to the x equals y. This is the small x,
equals y. This is the small x, private key. So g to the x equals y.
And g to the k, k is the one time private key. Well, this equals r.
We can see from the first signature generation, g to the k equals r. And thus we have y to the r,
y is the public key of Alice. So Bob can use Alice public key, and this r is the signed
signature. And r to the s, s is another signed signature. And p is a public key. And thus Bob
can verify gx, capital X, equals y to the r times r to the s. If they're equal, that means the message
is signed by Alice. So we have the mathematical
the equations, derivation to guarantee. Well, this result is correct to show the signature is
really generated by Alice, because I'm using Alice, the public key here, to do the verification.
Okay, let's look at one example. So in this example,
so the public key is 11, p is 11, the base g generator is 2,
well, 2 is the generator of z11. And public key is, the private key is 3. So public key is
And public key is, the private key is 3. So public key is g to the x, 3,
g to the x, that is 2 to the 3 mod 11. That's 8. Suppose the message value is 9, and we choose
the one time key k to be 7. So k, 7, and p minus 1, 10, the relative prime, and we can get k
minus 1. So k minus 1, in this example, I tell you the result is 3. And we calculate the signature
r to be g to the k. So base is 2 to the 3, 2 to the k is 7.
The mod p mod 11, the result here is 7. So s will be a value to be k minus 1
times the message minus the private key x times r mod p minus 1.
And the value should be, this is 3 times the message is 9, the private key is 3, r is 7,
and this result is 3 times
minus 12.
So this equals minus 36. This is congruent to 4 because we mod 10.
And thus the sign message should be, well, the message is 9, with r to be 7, and s to be 4.
In the verification, we compare these two data. The first one is gx.
The first one is gx. g, the base is 2, message is 9, mod p, p is 11, and this result is 6.
y is the public key, is 8 from here, y is here. r is, this is r, this is s.
So r is 7 times, 7 to the s is 4, mod 11. This result is also 6.
The equal, that means the signature is correct.
Any question?
Okay, in part three, we talk about another signature, and this one is quite important.
This is called the bland signature. In some cases, we need to have the bland signature,
and we look at what's meaning for bland signature. The basic idea is that a sender
makes a sender to send message m without knowing m. Therefore, blandly,
this is needed in some e-commerce applications.
In another application, just like in the voting scenario, what's your vote?
You don't want to disclose your voting result to some officer. The officer needs to sign his
signature on your form. So this is another case. Well, when you guarantee that, well,
the form contains the correct signature from the officer. However, the officer will not know
your voting form, your voted result.
So this is a bland signature, just like, well, this is a scenario. Someone can sign
the signature. Well, in this hard copy, that's fine.
Bland, her eyes will not see your content, but can generate the signature. And we won't have
the same process in the e-commerce in two parties.
So bland signature can be generated in the following procedures.
So we assume that, well, the original message is m. Of course, we sent something different
to the sender, right? So it cannot be m. That means from m, we generate m prime.
m prime is different. So m prime will not disclose your data information.
m cannot be obtained by the sender, and m prime will be signed by sender. So sender will sign
m prime to get a signature s prime. So for m prime,
we'll assume that we are using the RSA algorithm. So m prime to get signature s prime.
To generate signature, that means we will use the private key to generate the signature.
D mod n, we have the signature. But
in the RSA, suppose in the RSA, this signature generation algorithm,
the message, I'm using my private key, we generate the signature s prime.
Okay, this s prime will be returned to the sender. So sender now can compute the sender's
signature s of m. That means at the sender side, sender will try to generate s from s prime.
This is the arm blinding procedure. So this is called the blinding procedure.
Now this is the arm blinding procedure. And this s, well, the generation s should equal
m to the d mod n equals s. We need to guarantee s. Okay, this s contains to be the correct
signal from the sender. That means it equals the m to the d mod n. So d is the private key of the
sender. So it looks to be quite just like a magic, magical trick, right? I do not have your
private key, but somehow I will generate this s. It contains, it equals the message m
to the d mod n. d is the sender's private key. I don't have it, but I can generate the s.
The process can be viewed in this diagram. Well, this is Alice and this is Bob. Alice is the sender.
Bob is the sender.
So what we've done in this process is, in the blinding process, we will multiply m with another
key. In the blinding process, in the blinding process, we will multiply m with another data.
And this data r is called the one-time key.
r is a one-time key, random key. So this r, we will, in fact, Alice will choose the data r. r to be
one-time key. And m will times r to the e, and then mod p.
And m will times r to the e, and then mod p. So this m prime will be sent to Bob.
Alice will choose this r. This r is unknown to Bob. And in this way, m prime will
can conceal the original message m. Is this right?
The m prime will be sent to Bob. This message contains some random number r.
Bob has no idea about r. Thus, Bob cannot get any information from m.
So Bob will do this signing process. The signing is quite simple to Bob. So Bob will apply his
private key d to sign to generate the signature s prime. The s prime will be returned to Alice.
So let's see, s prime equals m prime to the d mod p. So m prime equals m times r e,
this to the d mod p. This equals m to the d times r mod p.
To the e d mod p.
Right? Well, according to RSA algorithm, RSA, we know that
r to the e d is congruent to 1 mod p, or previously with mod n. But here we simply use p.
That's the same thing, right?
So you can refresh your memory. m to the e d is congruent to n mod n.
And we apply the public key e, apply the private key d again. We can get the original message m
in the RSA algorithm. So here, the r e d will get back to r, that one time key again,
1 mod p. So this one will generate, this one equals m d times r mod p.
So this is the s prime. Is that clear?
Okay, this s prime will be obtained by Alice.
So Alice got s prime. From s prime, Alice will divide this s prime by r
So she will get m to the d times r divided by r mod p. And this equals m d mod p.
s prime divided by r equals s prime times r minus 1.
The times r minus 1, that's a module inverse.
So you see, s prime times r equals s prime times r minus 1.
Not because if both sides, we times r, we times r, we mod p, of course this can be canceled, right?
This is prime. And according to definition, r minus 1 times r, this is 1 mod p.
So of course, with this s prime divided by r, in fact equals s prime times r minus 1.
r minus 1 is a module inverse. So how can we do the division operation?
Division can be translated to the multiplication of the modular inverse.
Okay, so in nature 2, we studied the modular inverse.
We just guarantee modular inverse times the r mod p equals 1. That's a requirement.
The eyes can get s prime from Bob. So eyes will divide s prime by r.
Or we say s prime times r to the minus 1. Then we can get this is s.
For message m, it's signature to be signed by Bob. This signature is m to the d mod p.
So this for Bob, the public key is e p. This is the public key. And private key
is d, right? For Bob. Then you can see this is indeed
is generated by using Bob's private key based on the original message m.
We have this signature. Although Alice has no idea of Bob's private key,
but she can successfully generate the signature s. In this signing process,
Bob has no idea of the original message m. So eyes can know this r.
Of course, eyes can calculate r minus 1. When eyes obtain s prime from Bob,
so eyes can calculate s prime times r minus 1 mod p, then this equals the signature s.
So this is the blind signature generation process.
We have the charms plus signature scheme. This scheme is exactly the process illustrated in this page.
So you can see in this transplant signature, we assume that we're using the RSA algorithm.
And suppose Bob's public key is n and e. His private key is d. The message is m.
m should be smaller than n. And Alice chooses a one-time key k.
k should be in the range from 0 to n. We will guarantee that gcd n k is 1.
So this will guarantee that we have the k must 1 mod n.
k is a randomly chosen number. This is called the blinding factor.
In the blinding process, Alice will compute n times k to the e. Alice knows k.
And in this blinding process, well, when Bob applied his signature, applied his private key d,
and this m prime d equals this one.
m to the d times k times e d.
Well, in this way, the random number k with an exponent d can be actually can be cancelled.
We already put the exponent part with a value of e. So e times d mod n. Actually, this equals 1.
So in the on-branded case, we have a random number k with an exponent d.
Actually, this equals 1. So in the on-branding, the message we want to get from s prime to s.
So s prime is the signature obtained by Alice. So Alice can get
s prime times the k must 1. So this will get the original signature.
The reason is because s prime, this is s prime.
So s prime equals m d is equal to m d times k mod n. So from s prime to s,
we can simply multiply s prime by k must 1. This will generate the signature s.
So this is the whole process. You can see this is the m prime. m prime to d, we have m d, this is s, this is k.
You have mod n, e d.
In our RSA algorithm, e d, we choose e d such that it equals, it is congruent to 1 mod phi.
This is a guarantee that k e d mod n equals k.
So thus, we can get the s. This is the signature.
And this signature equals this part
is s prime.
Okay, now we look at this exercise. Suppose we have the copy key to be
e equals 5, n is 1, 1, 9. So 1, 1, 9 equals 7 times 17, right?
This p to be 7, q to be 17. The requester wants a signature on the message m equals
37. Suppose he chooses a random blending factor R to be 29. So we need to guarantee that g c d
R n is 1. In this way, we can calculate our must 1 mod n.
So what's the private key of Sonar? We have the public key, e and n. We are able to calculate
the Sonar's private key. And then we should apply the blending phase.
So suppose this step 1, step 2, blending phase, step 3, signing phase, step 4 on blending phase.
In the blending phase, that means the message m times R is one time key. We apply the same
message m times R is one time key. We apply the public key of the Sonar, right?
This is the blending phase. We get m prime. In the signing phase,
this is quite simple. The Sonar will apply his private key to do the signing. That's the m prime
to apply the private key d to generate the s prime. In the on-blending phase, it is
done by the requester. He will get the signature s from s prime times R one time key,
the module inverse of this R mod n.
OK, so this is an exercise. Let's have a break for 10 minutes. So in 10 minutes,
you can try to solve this exercise. OK, so let's have a break for 10 minutes.