Okay. Good evening, everyone. Today is our lecture two. So, lecture two, we talked about
the number theory. Totally, we have four parts for today's lecture. The part one is about
the divisibility, and from divisibility, we'll talk about the Euclidean algorithm. So, this
one is GCD, how we calculate the GCD value. First, we look at the divisibility. This concept
says that we have a long zero b, so b divides a evenly. That means if a can be represented
as n times b for some n, where a, b, and n are both integers, so one example is just like
a 3 divides 6. So, here a is 6, b is 3. So, 6 equals 2 times 3, right? So, n is 2. In
this equation, we can see there is no remainder on division. So, we can represent this relation
to be b divides a, b divides a evenly, and we say that b is a divisor or a factor of a, and a is
divisible by b. So, 6 is a factor of 3, a factor of 6. So, 6 is divisible by 3. So, according to
this definition, we first look at the project dividers of 24. So, the divider of 24, we have
what? 1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 8, 12, 24. So, we have all these dividers of 24. So, the next example
is, minus 5 is a divider of 30, yes or no? Minus 5 divides 60, or 30, yes or no? Yes, right?
Because 30 can be represented as minus 5 times minus 6. So, we say yes. 17 is a divider of 0, yes or no?
Yes, right? Because 0 can be represented as 17 times 0. So, this b, this a, b cannot be 0.
For division, we have this division algorithm. So, this algorithm says that for any positive
integer n and any non-negative integer a, if we divide a by n, we can get an integer
quotient q and an integer remainder r. So, a can be represented as q times n plus r,
q is quotient, and r is a remainder. And r is a remainder, that means r should be
bigger than or equal to 0, but smaller than n. So, we divide a by n, and q is the quotient,
and this is the flow. Flow of a divides n. So, flow means the largest integer
that is smaller than or equal to the given data. For example, 3.3, the flow is 3,
the flow of 3 is 3. The largest integer that's smaller than or equal to the given data. So,
q is a quotient. And also, this r remainder, we can represent this one as a mod n, a mod n,
the remainder will be the result. And also, we use this symbol to represent the mod
operation to get the remainder to be the result.
So, to support that, we have a equals q times n plus r. So, this data is a, and in this x-axis,
you can see we have q times n, and plus this part, this distance to be r. So, one example is,
suppose a is 70, and n is 15. This is n, and this is the quotient to be 4, and 10 will be the
remainder, r. So, this is the relationship, quite easy. Okay, based on the division,
we look at this Euclidean algorithm, and this one is one of the basic techniques of number theory,
and according to this algorithm, we are able to determine the greatest common divider of the two
positive integers. So, first, we look at the order of greatest common divider, GCD value.
Okay, the greatest common divider of a and b, that's GCD a, b, e, is the largest integer
that divides both a and b. For example, GCD value of 0 and 0 will be what? 0, yeah, by default,
we set it to be 0. GCD a and 0 will be what? a. So, suppose if a can be negative, so we set to be
absolute value of a, a is an integer, right? GCD value a and b equals what? Can you imagine what's
going to be? It's going to be too complicated. So, this equals GCD
e a, right? The share is the same GCD value. Okay. So, how about the last one, GCD a times n,
and a will be what? a. To be more accurate, it is the absolute value of a. So, an equivalent
definition is the GCD value of n, b. That means we want to get the max k, and this k divides a,
and this k also divides b. Okay, the maximum number of this k. We look at this example,
GCD 6 and 18 will be what? What's the value? 6, right? Because 18 is 6 times 3. The maximum
divisor for these two numbers is 6. And this is GCD value. And based on the GCD value, we define
that two integers a and b are relatively prime if their GCD value is 1. So, GCD value is 1. We say
they are relatively prime. This is an important concept. Are 8 and 15 relatively prime? Yes or
no? So, we say yes. The reason is because if we leave all positive divisors of 8 and 5,
8 and 15, we can find that the positive divisors of 8, we have 1, 2, 4, 8, and 15, we have 1,
3, 5, 15. So, the largest common divisor of 8 and 15 is 1. So, this shows GCD value,
8, 15 is 1. So, we say these two data, they are relatively prime. Okay?
So, how to calculate two integers, their GCD value, we have this Euclidean algorithm.
And this is a recursive algorithm. So, this one can quickly calculate the result. The GCD value,
the procedure is if q is 0, the result is p. And here, we suppose in this example,
in this representation, we suppose that q is bigger than or equal to 0, but smaller than p.
Okay? So, if q is 0, the result is p. This is easy to understand because GCD,
p0 is p. So, p is the largest common divisor of both p and 0. Otherwise,
we calculate it equals GCD q and p percent q. So, p percent q means the remainder R.
Because we can represent p to be q times n plus R. So, this GCD,
pq equals here means GCD q and R. Right? The reason is because, well, the GCD value means
the divisor of both p and q. So, p can be represented as, suppose p equals s times
the GCD value. Okay? No problem, right? GCD is the divisor of p. So, we represent p to be
s times GCD value. And q is also the model of this GCD. So, q can be represented as,
let's say, t times GCD value times n. And R, we have the remainder to be R.
And then this R equals s minus t times n times GCD value. Okay? R equals this one.
In other words, the GCD value is also a divisor of R.
That true? Okay. So, in other words, we want to calculate the GCD value of both p and q.
So, GCD value is a factor of p, is a factor of q. And also, we find that GCD is also a factor of
R from this equation. Right? GCD is also a factor of R. And this implies, well, if we want to calculate
GCD p, q, then this value can be calculated by the GCD of q and R. So, GCD must be the factor of
q and R simultaneously. So, because q and R are the values to be much smaller than q. Okay? So,
in this way, and finally, we recursively call this function. Otherwise, if q is not 0, we get
this q and R. And both q and R will be much smaller than t and q. We recursively call this function.
And finally, the R position can be 0. And we have t to be the output.
So, here is a flow to apply the Euclidean algorithm. So, suppose here we start, we want to get
the GCD a and b. And suppose a to be bigger than b. If yes, we divide a by b and put in the remainder.
So, this means a can be represented as a equals b times n plus R. And we look at R. If R is bigger
than 0, we replace a with b. So, this GCD a, b equals GCD b and R. Until R equals 0,
then the result, the GCD a, b, or we say it is b, R equals, if R is 0, the result is b at this moment.
Now, we look at this example. Suppose we want to get the GCD value
7, 10, and 3, 10. Yeah, here. We want to calculate this value. So, this one, well, this is p,
t is 7, 10, q is 3, 10, and this is R. According to the Euclidean algorithm, this one equals
the GCD value, q is 3, 10, R is 90, q and R. And here we continue this process. So, this is q,
this is R, and this is R1. So, this equals the GCD value, q is 90. Now, we have equals
this p, this is q, so this is q, this R equals R, R is 90, and R1, 40. So, this is
R, this is R1. So, every step you can see the p, r becomes smaller compared to the previous
p, q, and we continue this process. This is R, this is R1, we have R2, so this equals GCD,
R1, R2, 40, and R2 is 10. And we continue this process. So, we have R1 and R2 plus 0. 0 is R3,
right? And this equals GCD, R2, and R3. So, R2 is 10, R3 is 0. So, because the R value is 0,
and the output is this 10. So, after 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 5 steps, we get the result to be 10.
And this is a positive to calculate the GCD value by applying the Euclidean algorithm.
Another example is suppose we have this a, b, a, b, both n, b are very large. And well, even no
matter how large it is, we can quickly get the result after a number of steps. So, this is a,
b, this is q, and R1. And GCD a, b equals GCD. So, here is a equals b times q1 plus R1. So, this
equals b, R1. So, b, R1. And we recursively call the calculation. So, this equals GCD,
R1, R2. So, R1 is here, R2 is a remainder. So, we continue to process until we have.
So, it equals GCD in this row, R7, and R8. And equals GCD, R8, R9. So, R8 is this one, R9.
Is this one. And continually, we have equals GCD, R9, R10.
R sub 10, okay? This one. Because R sub 10 is 0, so, this one equals R9. And this is an output.
To be the value of this, it needs to be 10b.
So, everything looks fine, right? At this moment. If, well, everything is fine,
can you do the calculation of this exercise one? I'll give you three minutes. You tell me what's
the result. The GCD is 93 and 16.
What's the result for this? One. Okay. So, we can repeat. We can use the Euclidean
algorithm to calculate. So, this 93 can be represented as 16 times 5 plus 13.
And 13, 16. So, next one, we look at 16 and 13. 16. 16 equals 13 times 1 plus 3. And we look at
13 and 3. 13 equals 3 times 4 plus 1, right? And we have 3 and 1. So, 3 equals 1 times 3 plus 0.
So, these three, this one is GCD 31. So, finally, this one equals GCD 31 and 10.
So, this one. So, this corresponds to this row. This corresponds to this row. Equals 10.
Okay. This is a very easy part. Part one, just an appetizer. Okay?
Now, we go to part two. Based on our understanding of the Euclidean algorithm,
how to calculate the GCD value. So, now we need to move to part two about the modular arithmetic.
And then we need to learn the expanded Euclidean algorithm to get the modular inverse.
So, modular inverse is an important concept in the cryptography.
Okay. First, we look at the modular arithmetic. The modulus was a modulus in this modular operation.
Suppose we have A to be an integer and N is a positive integer. We can define A mod N to be
the remainder value where A is divided by N. And this integer N is called the modulus.
Suppose for given integer A, A can be represented as Q times M plus R. We note that
Q is quotient, right? And R is the remainder. Then A can be represented as this is the Q
value times N plus this is R value. R value can be represented as A mod N. A mod N. A divided by N,
we want to know what the remainder value. So, for example, 11 mod 7 was our result.
4, right? 11 equals 7 plus 4. So, 4 is a remainder. How about minus 11 mod 7? What do we want?
So, minus 11 can be represented as 7 times minus 2 plus 3, right? Plus 3. So, normally,
we want to have our long negative value to be the remainder. So, this one is 3.
For the mod operation, we have this concept, congruent mod N. Two integers A and B are said
to be congruent mod N if A mod N equals B mod N. This is written as A is congruent to B mod N.
So, both of them divided by N have the same remainder.
For example, 73. So, 73 can be represented as
23 times 3 plus 4. And that 73 is congruent to 4 mod 23, right? So, 4 divided by 23,
the remainder is 4. And 73 divided by 23, the remainder is 4. So, they're the same. We say
they are congruent when we have mod 23 in this operation. And 21 is congruent to 1 when mod N.
Okay. Now, if A is congruent to 0 mod N, that means N is a factor of A.
N is a factor of A. First, A divided by N, the remainder will be 0. The remainder will be 0.
Okay. We look at this one. Actually, this is a very important zero. So, this one says that
if GCD value of U and Z is 1. So, U and Z is 1, means these two are relative prime.
So, these two numbers are relative prime. Then U times X is coming to U times Y mod Z
UZ are relative prime. This U can be cancelled. And we have X is congruent to Y mod Z.
So, this is a good problem. So, one example is 3 times 3 is 9 is congruent to 3 times 11.
This is congruent to 1 when we take the mod 8. Because 3 and 8 are relative prime,
so this implies this 3 can be cancelled. This implies 3 is congruent to 11 when we take mod 8.
However, although we have 3 times 4 is congruent to 5 times 4 is congruent to 4
when we have the mod 8 operation. Well, we cannot cancel this form.
So, the reason is because 4 and 8 are not relative prime. If we move 4 from both sides,
left hand side and right hand side, can we get 3 is congruent to 5 mod 8? Of course not, right?
So, the reason is because the common factor 4 is not relative prime to 8. So, it cannot be cancelled.
Only if the common divisor number 3 is relative prime to the mod 8, then 3 can be cancelled.
This is a good problem.
Some other good problem is if we want to calculate a plus b mod n, we can first
calculate a mod n and then plus b mod n. This will make the result to be much smaller and to have
an easier calculation and similar for the minus operation and the multiplication operation.
So, one example is suppose we want to calculate 2 1 1 mod 8.
So, 2 1 1 mod 8 should be 3, 1 to 5 mod 8 will be 5. So, these two, the sum
the sum mod 8 equals the mod result 3 plus 5 mod 8 and this should be 0.
For the minus also, we can have this equation to quickly get the result. So, 2 1 1 is 3,
minus 5, this mod 8, the result is what? The result is 6. Minus 2, we have 1, it should be 6.
And this multiplication equals 3 times 5, mod 8, the result is what? 7.
Okay, we look at this table. This table suppose this row represents
so this row we have a and this column we have b and we have in the table which shows
the result a plus b mod 8.
0 plus 0, the result mod 8 is 0. And also we can find in this diagonal line,
the result is 0. So, 1 plus 7 is 8, mod 8 is 0. So, everyone we can find a corresponding value here
such that the sum mod 8 is 0. This is the addition operation.
Well, here we show the result to be a times b mod 8 result. So, this is a, this is b plus for
number 1 times 1, mod 8 is 1. However, for 2 times something, if b is 2, the whole row
we cannot find any number to be 1. So, in the multiplication, we look at the result, the product
mod 8 to be 1. So, in the row for b plus 2 cannot find anyone, if b equals 3, we find a value such
that a equals 3, there mod 8 result is 1. So, the sum there can be 1 plus not all the a or b value
we can find ourselves for the product value mod 8 to be 1.
So, then we define the additive and the multiplicative inverse mod 8.
So, this is the definition of the inverse value mod given number 8. So, we define that the additive
inverse is your w plus minus w is coming to 0 mod 8. And this minus w is called the additive
inverse, additive inverse, because we have this addition, right, we add them together. This is
for the additive inverse of w mod 8. Well, if w is 0, so minus w will be 0. So, here is
additive inverse, 0 plus 0, mod 8 is 0. If w is 1, the additive inverse will be 7, 1 plus 7, mod 8
is 0. For every w, we have corresponding minus w to be the additive inverse of w mod 8. We have
all the values here. However, for multiplicative inverse, so multiplicative inverse defines as
w times the w to minus 1. And the result is coming to 1 when we have the mod 8
operation. This is the definition to be the multiplicative inverse of w. We denote this value
to be w to minus 1. If w is 1, this modular inverse should be 1. 1 times 1, here is multiplication.
1 times 1 is 1, so mod 8 is 1. However, for 2, 4, 6, we do not have the modular inverse,
the multiplicative inverse mod 8. For 3, w equals 3, the w to minus 1 is 3. 3 times 3 is 9.
This is congruent to 1. We have mod 8 operation. Check here.
For some w, we have the multiplicative inverse. This w to the minus 1 is called the multiplicative
inverse. Some properties for this modular operation are, for example, for this Zn,
so Zn is set with all integers from 0, 1 to a mass 1. We have 40 properties. The first one is
commutative loss. That means for addition and multiplication, we can swap the first and second
data to the result of the same. For solutive loss means, well, for this addition or multiplication,
we can first calculate the first two or the second two to the result of the same.
Then, distributive law means the w can be in this parenthesis, w times x plus y equals w times x
plus w times y. Identity means some data plus the w itself or times w itself equals itself.
So this identity in addition is 0. In multiplication is 1.
In two different scenarios, the identity value will be different.
A detailed inverse will be minus w. That means for each w in this set, there exists a z such that
w plus z is 0 mod m. So this z, we always can find this z. So this z, we call it to be
a detailed inverse, to be mass w.
For example, if w is 1, then z is a mass 1. If w is 2, then z is a mass 2.
We can always find this z to be a detailed inverse for a given w.
Will we care about the modular inverse for the multiplication? This is our equation.
Now, we said that x is a modular inverse of a mod d if a times x mod d equals 1.
Here is a definition of a modular inverse for the multiplication.
x is denoted as a to the mass 1 mod b. So between a times x mod b equals 1, x is denoted to be
the multiplicative inverse of a mod b. So x is a modular inverse.
So we have examples here. Because 3 times 5 is equal to 1 mod 7. 3 times 5 is 15.
So we say 3 is a modular inverse of 5 mod 7.
In other words, because this definition is 5 to the mass 1 times 5 mod 7 is 1.
So this 5 mod 1 modular inverse of 5 equals what?
Equals what?
This is a mass 1 to the mass 1 mod 7 equals what?
So which number is a modular inverse of 5?
Which number?
The definition is 5, modular inverse of 5 is 5 mass 1 times 5 mod 7 should be 1.
And we have 3 times 5 mod 7 is 1. So this modular inverse of 5 equals 3.
And similarly, because 7 times 7 is equal to 1 mod 16. So this 7 represents modular inverse of 7.
So this 7 to the mass 1 mod 16 is 7.
However, there is no modular inverse for 8 mod 14. So that means we don't have this 8 mass 1,
this value such that 8 mass 1 times 8 is equal to 1 mod 14.
No such modular inverse.
No such data such that the demand times 8 mod 14 equals 1.
In fact, we have this theorem. There exists a modular inverse for A mod B
even though only if A is relative prime to B.
So that means we have this A to the mass 1 modular inverse of A. So A times A mass 1 is
congruent to 1 mod B. And this implies GCD AB must be 1. So in this example, because the GCD
So in this example, because the GCD 814 is what?
The greatest common divisor of 8 and 14 is what? 8 and 14 is what?
2, right? It is not 1. The not relative prime. So we don't have the 8 to the mass 1.
Not 1.
So that means we don't have the modular inverse for 8 mod 14.
Well, the modular inverse is critical. The reason is because in the RSA algorithm,
we have public key, we have private key, E and D, right? So E is the public key
and D is the private key.
To get public key, we require that E times D is congruent to 1 mod some value. And this value is 5m.
You see? E times D. So E is the modular inverse of E mod 5m. This public key and private key,
that relationship is a modular inverse relationship.
In this public key scheme, in this RSA algorithm, that's the reason we need to
amplify the modular inverse scheme.
So in RSA algorithm, we need to decide the public key, even the public key.
The relationship should satisfy E times D with congruent to 1 mod 5m.
Okay, so now we want to have a formal way to calculate the modular inverse of A mod n
according to the calculation. To do the calculation, we can resort to this phase of identity.
So phase of identity states that for any given integer A and B,
we can find such integer x and y such that A times x plus
A times x plus B times y equals their GCD value, GCD AB. So this is a phase of identity
for any given integers and B. There exist x and y, integers x and y to satisfy this equation.
Okay, so this phase of identity tells you that if N, B are relative to 1,
or relative to 1, so if
GCD A and B equals 1, so AB relatively to 1,
then we are able to calculate the A's modular inverse mod B.
So what does it mean? If GCD AB equals 1, we can find such A x plus B y equals 1.
Well, at both sides, we have mod, for example, mod B. If A x plus B y mod B,
this equals 1 mod B. For such, we take the mod operation. So this implies your B times 1,
this multiple B, this part is 0. Okay, so that means, well, the left-hand side equals A x mod B
is 1. So this implies A x is relative to 1 mod B. So this x is what? x is the modular inverse of A.
So this x equals A to the mod 1 mod B.
x is the modular inverse of A mod B in this case. According to this phase of identity,
if A and B are with fun, then we can find this x and y. So x, we call it to be the modular inverse of A mod D.
We find the modular inverse of A successfully in this case.
And similarly, if at both sides with mod A, so this implies A x plus B y,
we take the mod A operation. So this equals 1 mod A, and this A times x mod A is 0.
So B y mod A equals 1. In other words, B y is coming to 1 mod A. So this y represents
modular inverse of B when it has a mod A operation.
So here, this is an implication of the modular inverse for this parameter A x and B y.
So this is an implication for this phase of identity in this equation.
Because the result is gcd value, how to calculate gcd value? We can use the Euclidean algorithm.
Euclidean algorithm can help you to calculate the gcd value. And we can use extended Euclidean
algorithm to solve the initial equation to find x1. Once you find x, you find the modular inverse
of A. So x is here, y is here. But we can use the extended Euclidean algorithm to find the modular
inverse of A, that's x. Modular inverse of B, that's y. Now let's look at how we can
use the extended Euclidean algorithm to find the modular inverse of 911 mod 999.
So we won't find the modular inverse of 911 mod 999 according to the Bezos identity. If this one is A,
this one is B. So we have A x plus B y equals gcd A B. Is that right?
A is 911, B is 999. First we need to guarantee that this gcd
911 999, it is 0, or it is 1. If it is 1, we can find some x. So x will be modular inverse of A
mod B according to the Bezos identity.
So here you can see we satisfied this equation. We say x is a modular inverse of A mod B.
That's exactly. x is a modular inverse of A mod B. A is here, B is here. If their gcd value is 1.
So now we look at how we can calculate this modular inverse.
So the first step is we still need to guarantee that the gcd A B is 1. We apply the Euclidean
algorithm to guarantee that this is true. So from the Euclidean algorithm, this is A, this is B,
this is R, this is B, this is R, this is R1, this is R, this is R1, R2, so on and so forth.
So this is R2, this is R1, this is R2, R3, so this is R2, this is R1,
this is R2, this is R3, this is R4, so R4 will be the result.
We finally have 1 to be the output of this gcd value of 999 and then 911.
So because their gcd value is 1, that means we can find the corresponding x and y.
How do we find this x and y? So you see, we go to the
reverse one. We trace it back. From this one here, one can be represented as R2 minus 5 times R3.
26 minus 5 times 5. So this is R2, this is R3. And R3,
from the second row, R3 equals 31 minus 1 times 26 from this row.
So we can substitute 5 from the second row. So then, one can be represented as, this is R2,
some value of R2 with R1. Because R3 can be represented as, this is R1, this is R2.
R3 can be represented as some combination of R1, R2.
So 1 equals some beta times R1 times R2. And R2, we can finally, we can, according to
this row, R2 can be represented as R minus R1. So this 26 can be represented as R
minus 2 times R1. So finally, one can be represented as R times R something
plus or minus something times R1. So 31 can be represented as, so one equals,
this R1 can be represented as, number one is B, and it is R. So finally, one can be represented as
B plus R, some combination. And R can be represented as A, B, some combination.
So R comes from here. So R, this 1 equals this B, some number times this A, this B.
And finally, one can be represented as this A, this is X, this is B, this is 1.
So finally, we have 1, we are putting the betas, and then A times X because B times 1 equals 1.
So in this example, because GCD value, so A is 999 times 176.
So this is A, this is X, plus B, 911 times minus 193. This equals GCD, A and B, is 1.
So this is, X is here, A is here, B is here, Y is here, then here, and this we will trace back.
This tracing back procedure is called the extended Euclidean algorithm.
So of course, X represents X equals A to the minus 1, the module inverse of A mod B.
So X is,
sorry, A is 911, right? So here is, change it, A is here, X is here,
B is here, Y is here. So X is equals mass 193 mod 999.
So we take the positive value, the positive should be,
R, X should be 806.
So in this example, the module inverse of 911, it is 806.
Because 806 times 911 mod 999, it is 1.
The result of 806 times 911 is coming to 1 mod 999.
So the basis of this equation implies this equation.
So here, this is here, this part is here, change it.
So A is here, this part is X, E is here, this part is 1.
This is A, this is B, this is X, 911 is B, sorry, this is 911 is X, so this is X.
So finally, we make it to be correct on the equation.
So the second page actually shows, because according to the basis equation, this GCD
A is 911, B is here, can be represented as, this is A, this is X, and this B, this is Y.
So we have 806 is a module inverse of A mod B, this is the module inverse.
In this example, what's the B mod 1?
B mod 1 is what?
B mod A, B mod 1 is what?
Is what, right?
176 is B mod 1, because B mod 1 times B mod A equals what?
Okay, previously, we have, in exercise one, we have the GCD 93, 16, equals what, right?
So this is how we can find the module inverse of 16, modular 93.
So can you use 10 minutes to solve this result?
Okay, this has a break, 10 minutes. Okay, after break, we continue.