Okay, now let's look at the result for this problem.
The first step is to calculate the private key D for the given E and N value.
So here because E is quite small, it's 5, when E equals 5, 3, you can try this way to
calculate the private key D.
So previously we have said because in the RSA algorithm, we will make sure E D is congruent
to 1 mod phi n.
So this implies E D can be represented as k times phi n plus 1.
So this implies D can be represented as k times phi n plus 1 divided by E.
In this example, n is 1, 1, 9, so phi n is 6 times 16, that's 96.
So this equals k times 96 plus 1 divided by 5, and you can try k equals 1 whether we
can find an integer or not.
So k equals 1 we cannot, k equals 2 we cannot, k equals 3 we cannot, k equals 4, okay.
If k equals 4 and then we have this D is 4 times 96 plus 1 divided by 5, that is 77.
Now of course you can apply the extended Euclidean algorithm to get D, that will be fine as well,
but the result will be same to be 77.
That's step one.
So step two is m prime equals n times R E mod n.
So this equals m is 37 times R, 29, E is 5, mod n is 1, 1, 9.
You apply all the numbers here, you will get m prime to be, to be line.
So step three, the signing process is simple, s prime equals m prime to the D mod n, m prime
is 9, D is the private key 77, mod 1, 1, 9, you will get the result to be 25.
Step four, you need to get all mass ones first, mod n.
So how can you calculate all mass one?
You have R to be 29 and to be 1, 1, 9.
So you need to use the extended Euclidean algorithm to get all mass one here.
I will not repeat that process.
The result is all mass one is 78 in this example.
So you will get s equals s prime times all mass one, mod n.
So here s prime is 25 times all mass one is 78, mod n is 1, 1, 9.
So this result is 46.
So this 46 of course will equal m to the D mod n.
In this example, m is 37, D is 77, mod 1, 1, 9.
You can double check it, so I will not check it here.
And this is the four steps to have the whole process to finish the blank signing and to
get the signature by the requester in this example.
So we have some left exercises for you.
You can try to solve this problem by yourself first.
And before your mid-term test, we have the mid-term review and I will show you the whole
process how to get the correct solutions to these questions.
So that's for the lecture four about the digital signature.
Well, in this subject, we have the topic about e-payment, right?
In the first class, we have the brief introduction about e-payment.
So now we look at the specific protocols used in the e-payment.
In today's lecture five, we'll talk about the SET, this e-payment protocol, what's
the meaning, what's the steps to be used for the message check in this e-payment protocol.
So part one is about the SET architecture and dual signature.
So you can see the signature part is very important because in the payment, we need
to do the user authentication.
How can we do the authentication?
That means you need to show your correct signature.
In the SET protocol, this is a protocol designed to secure bank card transactions initiated
on open networks, open networks just like in today's internet, wireless internet, right?
SET means secure electronic transaction.
The SET specifications cover the roles like the following, like we have the cardholder,
you are the cardholder, you're the customer, we have the merchant, just like you're doing
the online shopping, right?
Online is some store, online shops, and we have payment gateway.
So you will see this one, the role later, and we have certification authority.
Certification authority is CA.
The purpose of CA is for everyone to get a valid certificate containing
your public key.
So in this SET protocol, we have the cardholder, we have the merchant, we have the cardholder's bank,
we have the merchant's bank.
So at least we have four parties, right?
We have four parties.
That means for their complications, they need to generate signatures for those indications.
We guarantee I'm talking to the one, you're the right person, I communicate with you.
And how can we guarantee you're the right person?
I need to check your signature.
How can we make sure your signature is correct?
You must show me your public key to be verified by this CA center.
So we assume CA is a trusted third party.
So you have your certificate.
That certificate is authorized by the third party.
Just like you're holding the polio's degree, right?
In that certificate, it contains polio's authorization, some message, approval.
This is your degree.
And same thing here.
The certificate will contain your public key to be issued by the CA.
So when you show the certificate to the receiver, you see, this is my public key.
You can trust my public key because it is issued by polio.
So you use this public key to check my signature.
So you show your public key to the receiver.
Receiver will trust that certificate.
Because that certificate finally will contain the certification, the CS signature.
Just like your polio degree contains polio's signature, like here.
So people will verify whether your polio degree is true, is valid, or not.
So other people will use polio's public key to verify the signature in your degree.
So this is the logic.
OK, we look at the state architecture.
We have different participants.
Like, we are called holder.
This is the customer.
We are called holder's bank, customer's bank.
Just like your credit card bank, we have merchant, and also we have merchant's bank.
And also we have merchant's bank.
Always say this is a quire institution.
And well, the card holder, just like you, your customer, you can browse the internet.
You can place online order, right?
So through customer and merchant, we have the internet.
Internet is an open network.
We have the communications there.
They can browse the internet and place order.
The order information will be sent to you.
Now you have order information.
You want to order some TV.
That's order information.
And also you will place your payment information, your card information.
Your card information will be sent to the payment gateway.
And the order information will be verified by the merchant.
Merchant will know you're placing an order to buy a TV.
So your card information is a token, actually will be encrypted.
So the card information will be sent to the payment gateway.
And payment gateway will connect to a closed network between like the credit card company
and the merchant's bank.
So this one is a closed network.
For example, you can use SWIFT system to settle down all the transactions between different
banks.
Your card information will go through payment gateway, will be sent to your credit card
company to get approval.
Once your transaction request is approved, that means your credit card company will check
your signature to guarantee this is a real request from that card number, that holder.
And then if your signature is correct and your credit card still has the balance to
pay this order, then your request can be approved.
The approved information will be returned back to the merchant, the approval.
Approval just like there will be a token, contains this credit card's signature.
And later on, the token from the approval, the token will be used by the merchant to
claim the credit.
And the merchant will know from this approval message, this transaction request has been
approved and this transaction is approved.
That means, well, the request has been approved and this transaction is done, finished.
At the same time, you're the customer, you will receive a message from your credit card
company, just like this transaction is approved.
Later on, you need to pay this bill to your credit card company.
Okay, the merchant can use token to get credit from his bank.
And this bank will use token, same token, to settle down transactions between the bank
system.
Okay, in this architecture, we can look at some description here.
We have the card holder, customer, merchant, the CA center.
CA center is a trusted third party.
We trust this one to get a valid certificate.
And we have the payment gateway or all connected by the internet.
Each participant has a certificate from a set CA center.
So the certificate will have your certified public key.
As a customer, you will have your private key locally.
No one else knows your private key, right?
So you will generate your private key and it will be owned by you,
but you can have your public key to be certified by the CA center.
So the issuer and the acquirer institutions are linked by a closed and secure bank network,
just like the SWIFT system.
And the payment gateway bridges the open and closed network.
We have the payment gateway stand between the open and the closed network,
can transmit some message between these two systems.
Before we have the transaction, the first step is that we should have the registration
of the card holders and the merchants with a CA center.
Your registration will guarantee that you will have a certificate to be issued by the CA
and you will get the certificate.
This certificate will be sent to you, to the card holder and the merchants.
And then all the transactions, all transactions, we should guarantee the following properties,
like the authentication, confidentiality, and integrity for every transaction.
Transaction can be your order, it can be your payment request.
So authentication, how can we guarantee the authentication, the message?
Every transaction can be regarded as a message, right?
So message, when you guarantee the authentication, the message,
authentication means this message is really from Alice.
So what we should do is, normally we have H, M, the message, we take the hash function.
The message, we take the hash function, and based on the hash function, we use Alice,
private key, to generate the signature.
The private key,
the private key of Alice,
the public key of Alice,
so in this way, this is signature and the receiver will use Alice public key,
because public key
is given in this certificate.
POP of Alice.
Well, along with your message, you will also show your certificate to the receiver.
So this certificate contains your public key, and the receiver can use your public key in the
certificate to verify your signature is correct or not, to guarantee the authentication of the
message. Okay, we have the signature verification. Confidentiality means, well,
normally we use the symmetric encryption.
We have the symmetric encryption to encrypt the message, even though the message is transmitted
in the open network, in the internet, and in fact, no one can open this message, because
no one has this symmetric key K. Unless you send the key K to the receiver,
the right receiver can open this message. And integrity means, well, it is not modified.
And we said that the correct signature will guarantee the integrity of the message, right?
Because if a message becomes N prime,
N prime will have a different S prime. So this S prime cannot equal the S, the signature,
along with the message. That means your signature will guarantee both authentication and integrity.
The data, the message, the content will not be modified.
And we have the payment authorization. This will be done by your credit card company.
So once you provide your credit card number and you have your correct, your number,
credit card number, plus your valid signature,
then your request can be approved by your credit card company. So your credit card company has your
public key and you can generate the correct signature. Then you can get approval or you
can get the payment authorization from your credit card company. So later on, the payment,
once this transaction is done, the payment capture can initiate the request for
financial clearance on behalf of the merchant. So this means merchant
and claim credit from the transaction.
Of course, just like this payment authorization is a token, this token will be
sent to the merchant. So merchant has this token, and later on, this token will also be sent by the
credit card company. So the merchant can use this token to claim the credit, just like he sold
a TV to the customer and then he can get the credit.
Okay, we look at the message. How will the message be a clear message? This message can be
the order request and payment information. How this message will be processed in this payment
system. And how can we guarantee the authentication, confidentiality, and integrity?
And how can we guarantee the authentication, confidentiality, and integrity?
The message, we have the hash function, we get the digest, H, M.
So we use the sender's private key, we generate the signature, and suppose we are using the RSA
algorithm. So signature S equals H, M, to the D mod M, right? We have the signature. And signature
plus M will be the original, well, the whole message. And this message, we apply the symmetric
encryption. That means S plus M, we use a symmetric key K to do the encryption.
This key K is one-time symmetric key K. So this key K will be put in some, well,
as some loss for security purpose, we add some padding information. So this key K will be put here.
And then we use the receiver's public key to do the encryption. So this key K will be encrypted
by using the public key of the receiver, recipient.
Okay, then these two parts will be put together to become the transmitted message to be sent
to the receiver. So the receiver can get two parts, both the encrypted message and also the
encrypted secret key. So you can see, well, without key K, no one can get the original message M and
S, right? Or who can open the key K? Only the recipient.
Recipient will use, well, the key K, suppose we're using the RSA algorithm. So this key K,
this is like D1, key K, we use the recipient, we have the E2, N2, and D2, N2 to be his RSA key pair.
And this key K will be encrypted by using the receiver's public key.
So this is key K to the E, mod E2, mod N2. So this will be received by recipient. And recipient can
use his private key D2 to decrypt the key K. So this key K, E2, and he will use his private key D2,
mod N2 to get key K. And this key K can be used to
decrypt this message. And last, the recipient can open the encrypted message to get S signature
and the message M. Of course, the receiver will double check the signature is correct or not to
guarantee it is really from the customer or from the credit card company. Like that. Is that clear?
So we have signature to guarantee authentication,
to guarantee the message integrity.
And we have the symmetry encryption and the public key scheme here to guarantee
the message confidentiality.
But we guarantee authentication, confidentiality, and integrity of every transaction.
So encrypted means we guarantee the message is not discussed. Yeah. Any question?
So this is key K to the E, mod E2, mod N2. So this is key K to the E2, mod N2.
You mean the hash, right? Hash power, right? Okay. This is a good question. Well, the hash,
actually, this is necessary step. You will see without hash, there could be some attack.
The hash is a good property, one-way function. It's one-way function. You cannot fabricate a message.
But without hash, you can fabricate some signature. So you will see in this nature 5,
in nature 4, there is one exercise we call the signature forgery attack without hash function.
So here we just have hash function. You'll see when you try to solve that problem.
Yeah. Yeah, that's right. Yeah. So the hash function, just like we apply the public key
null hash function, shot, turn it, and the 56. And this encryption, just like we use AES,
the encryption, decryption algorithm, or the public key null, what are null is the private key. Okay.
Like here.
Just like here, the RSA algorithm is well known. What you don't know is only the private key,
like here. All the process, like the hashing, encryption, decryption, all the
these mechanisms are well known. The unknown part is only the private key.
Okay. We look at the previous slide, how the previous slide can be translated in a real
implementation. Suppose this is a clear text M, the M
after the next hash function shot 256, we get HM. So based on the HM, we have the detail signature.
Now this signature equals HM. Suppose we're using
the public key of the Alice, we can generate the signature. So the message M plus the signature S
and also Alice will provide her sunny certificate. So this sunny certificate contains E1 and E1.
Alice will use D1 to be her sunny private key. So this certificate will be sent to the receiver.
And then all the messages will be decrypted by using a one-time key K.
M plus S will be encrypted by the key K. And this key K will be put in an envelope plus
here just adding some padding bits to make it even more secure. And then the envelope
will be encrypted by using the public key of the recipient.
So this key K will be encrypted by using the recipient. Suppose we have the E2, N2,
and D2 will be the private key of the recipient. And the sender will use the E2
as the encryption key to generate the message to be sent along with the symmetric key encrypted
message. So all the messages will be sent to the receiver.
Okay, so this is how the message will be processed in the SET protocol. So in SET protocol,
another very important concept is called the dual signature. Dual signature can link elements of two
encrypted messages, each sent to a different recipient with the same signature. The dual
each sent to a different recipient with the same signature. We use the same signature, but
this signature can serve two purposes because it can link two encrypted messages.
Just like we have the message M1. So M1 is the order information.
Your order information is like you place an order to BioTV. And you have M2.
M2 is your account information.
So you will use your account to pay this order, right? Two messages. M1 will be sent to merchant.
M2, your account information will be sent to the payment gateway and will be sent to, finally,
to your credit card company. Your account information will not be known by your, by the merchant.
So we have two encrypted messages, but we will have one signature. So these two messages
will generate a single signature. So this will be sent together to the merchant
and to the payment gateway.
We have two receivers. So two messages, but we have a single signature. This single signature
is called the dual signature. Okay. And thus we can vote on this three signature, more signature
generation to be sent back and forth among different parties. So we have two receivers.
Okay. So in this procedure, a customer sends the purchase order to the merchant
to the M1 information and the payment instruction to the buyer's bank. So this is the M2 information.
The payment instructions are executed only after the merchant has accepted the purchase order.
The purchase order is M1. Merchant will guarantee M1 information is correct. However, merchant
cannot know the buyer's account number. M2 is not disclosed to the merchant. So M2 is revealed
revealed to the bank only.
And this is a requirement.
Well, at the same time, the bank processes the transaction without knowing the nature of the
purchase. So bank no idea about M1, no information.
Okay. We have two messages. So each will be sent to different destination. They will be encrypted,
but we have one signature.
Okay. For the detailed information about your signature, we will discuss it in the next class.
So today I stop here. We still have the project instruction today. So TA is here and then we will
start the project instruction five minutes later. Okay. So you can have a break. Thank you. So we
shall have a good holiday tomorrow.